<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Recap News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:30:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
    <atom:link href="https://raw.githack.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS/main/Semiconductor-RSS.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <item>
      <title>Celera Semiconductor Welcomes Industry Veteran Paul MacMillan as Vice President of Manufacturing Operations, Supply Chain and Quality</title>
      <link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/celera-semiconductor-welcomes-industry-veteran-paul-macmillan-as-vice-president-of-manufacturing-operations-supply-chain-and-quality-302635543.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;i&gt;— Celera Semi expands management team to support rapid production ramp&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;—&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;SANTA CLARA, Calif.&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Dec. 9, 2025&lt;/span&gt; /PRNewswire/ -- Celera Semiconductor, the leading analog IC supplier using AI to slash the cost and time to develop and supply analog ICs, has appointed Paul MacMillan to manage its supply chain and quality organizations.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;MacMillan will focus on building a world-class manufacturing capability to ensure rapid and reliable delivery of new analog ICs for Celera Semi&apos;s growing customer base.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&quot;We are ramping production hard through 2026 and for years to come,&quot; said Celera Semi&apos;s CEO Pat Brockett. &quot;I have seen Paul build and manage world class supply chains and quality organizations before. We are thrilled to have him in this critical role.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;MacMillan added, &quot;Celera&apos;s AI design automation platform is opening the doors for all our customers to get the exact analog ICs they want, fast. Our world-class supply partners which include Vanguard International Semiconductor and the ASE group ensure that our customers will be receiving high quality products at a competitive price and with the most responsive service in the industry.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Paul MacMillan holds a BSEE degree, and he initially worked in test development and product engineering at Motorola (now Freescale) and Telcom (now Microchip). Paul built and ran the supply chain at Summit Micro (now Qualcomm) from zero to supplying millions of ICs to the smart phone, consumer and networking industries.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Celera Semiconductor&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Celera Semiconductor is redefining the future of analog IC design. Using software acceleration based on its patented Nesto™ technology – the industry&apos;s first library of digital twins of analog functions— Celera Semiconductor is the first to offer full-custom or standard products in a fraction of the time of traditional semiconductor companies. Headquartered in Santa Clara, CA, Celera partners with world-class supply chain players to deliver high-performance, cost-efficient analog solutions at unprecedented speed. Maverick Silicon is the major investor in Celera.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573777-1&amp;amp;h=4050987521&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fedge.prnewswire.com%2Fc%2Flink%2F%3Ft%3D0%26l%3Den%26o%3D4541179-1%26h%3D1329714025%26u%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fc212.net%252Fc%252Flink%252F%253Ft%253D0%2526l%253Den%2526o%253D4475828-1%2526h%253D3542558854%2526u%253Dhttps%25253A%25252F%25252Fwww.celerasemi.com%25252F%2526a%253Dwww.celerasemi.com%26a%3Dwww.celerasemi.com&amp;amp;a=www.celerasemi.com&quot;&gt;www.celerasemi.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Maverick Silicon&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Maverick Silicon is an investment adviser focused on private semiconductor growth companies and related opportunities. This includes a focus on companies designing or producing chips, hardware, software or processes that accelerate or enable the performance of the broader infrastructure stack underlying artificial intelligence. Maverick Silicon is a division of Maverick Capital, a global $10B asset manager.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573777-1&amp;amp;h=3968221091&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fedge.prnewswire.com%2Fc%2Flink%2F%3Ft%3D0%26l%3Den%26o%3D4541179-1%26h%3D2854386590%26u%3Dhttps%253A%252F%252Fwww.mavericksilicon.com%252F%26a%3Dwww.mavericksilicon.com%252F&amp;amp;a=www.mavericksilicon.com%2F&quot;&gt;www.mavericksilicon.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;SOURCE Celera Semiconductor&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://rt.prnewswire.com/rt.gif?NewsItemId=NY40531&amp;amp;Transmission_Id=202512090900PR_NEWS_USPR_____NY40531&amp;amp;DateId=20251209&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/celera-semiconductor-welcomes-industry-veteran-paul-macmillan-as-vice-president-of-manufacturing-operations-supply-chain-and-quality-302635543.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:20:40 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>US-China tech thaw? Trump clears Nvidia H200 exports – why it matters</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3335774/us-china-tech-thaw-trump-clears-nvidia-h200-exports-why-green-light-matters?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_image_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/09/9cee4bd5-b47b-4302-8f11-c5e68707c1fe_9fe1b489.jpg?itok=zFsdHxbV&amp;amp;v=1765274522&quot; alt=&quot;9cee4bd5-b47b-4302-8f11-c5e68707c1fe_9fe&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;US President Donald Trump’s green light for Nvidia to sell H200 artificial intelligence (AI) chips in China signals a calculated shift to export older technology, according to analysts who see the move as aiming to fortify the US market share while dampening China’s urgency for self-reliance.  
But some predict an ongoing policy tug of war in the US between advocates of this week’s relaxation and those who prefer continued tight restrictions on hi-tech gear shipped to China.  
Trump said on Monday...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.scmp.com/economy/global-economy/article/3335774/us-china-tech-thaw-trump-clears-nvidia-h200-exports-why-green-light-matters?utm_source=rss_feed</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:09:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Is Copper Sintering the Key to Advancing Wide Band Gap Semiconductors?</title>
      <link>https://www.3dincites.com/2025/12/is-copper-sintering-the-key-to-advancing-wide-band-gap-semiconductors/</link>
      <description>&lt;h3&gt;By Rejoy Surendran and Xinpei Cao, Henkel Adhesive Technologies&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In the mid- to high-voltage power semiconductor sector, which enables EVs, telecom networks, energy infrastructure, and industrial innovation, wide band gap (WBG) semiconductors like gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC) are on their way to surpassing silicon (Si) for power discretes, power modules, and RF devices. Their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/wide-bandgap-semiconductor-market-to-reach-5-4-billion-globally-by-2032-at-13-2-cagr-allied-market-research-302004617.html&quot;&gt;projected annual growth rate of more than 13%&lt;/a&gt; over the next several years is proof of WBG’s performance superiority for high-power, high-temperature, high-frequency applications where they offer exceptional efficiency, excellent thermal conductivity, and higher breakdown voltages, making them indispensable for cutting-edge technologies in high-stakes markets.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;To fully harness the performance potential of WBG semiconductors, the die attach materials that bond the semiconductors to their packages must be able to cost-effectively accommodate WBG’s high heat and ensure efficient power transfer. Because of its proven thermal and electrical conductivity advantages, sintering (where particles are bonded through heat and pressure into a solid metal layer) has become the preferred die/substrate attach method over traditional soldering, as it can provide exceptionally high thermal conductivities and cope with the high-temperature operating environments (&amp;gt;200° C) WBG devices experience in some applications. Silver sintering is arguably the industry standard, but new developments in copper pressure-assisted sintering materials are challenging silver sintering’s dominance and have the potential to reshape the WBG semiconductor market.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h2&gt;Copper’s Competitiveness Challenges Silver’s Stronghold&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Silver’s high thermal conductivity (430 W/m-K) and electrical performance are why it has traditionally been favored for sintering WBG devices, even though it comes at a price premium. Copper, however, offers similar thermal conductivity at close to 400 W/m-K and electrical conductivity only slightly lower than silver. This performance parity at lower cost, combined with other advantages of copper, is driving &lt;a href=&quot;https://dm.henkel-dam.com/is/content/henkel/Copper-Sintering-for-High-Power-Modules-EDIT-VER&quot;&gt;copper-based sintering materials&lt;/a&gt; development that rivals – and in some cases exceeds – silver’s advantages. These include:&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliability:&lt;/strong&gt; Copper sintered joints exhibit excellent mechanical strength, maintaining structural integrity through thermal cycling, which is critical for high-reliability applications like automotive and aerospace, where prolonged exposure to high temperatures, humidity, and stress are the norm. Compared to silver, copper demonstrates resistance to electromigration, helping to minimize the possibility of degraded long-term performance. Finally, copper’s higher tensile strength and lower coefficient of thermal expansion (CTE) increase its potential for better reliability than silver-based materials.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost-of-Ownership and Sustainability:&lt;/strong&gt; Copper is notoriously more economical than silver, with the ability to deliver lower cost-of-ownership in high-volume production operations. In addition to its cost advantage, copper is a sustainable material. Copper mining has a lower environmental impact than silver, is more abundant, and recyclable. Finally, copper sintering processes have been shown to require less energy than silver sintering.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h2&gt;New Copper Sintering Technology Overcomes Obstacles to Power Ahead&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Historically, the challenges with copper-based materials have centered on their sintering difficulty.  Older-generation formulations required higher temperatures and higher pressures than silver materials to achieve complete sintering, which introduced potential damage to dies and substrates.  However, advances in sintering environments and innovative formulation approaches are mitigating these concerns, enabling thorough copper sintering without the need for excessive pressure and temperature. For instance, Henkel’s new pressure-assisted copper sintering material is engineered to overcome many shortcomings of conventional copper sintering formulas.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;This groundbreaking material, leveraging proprietary copper filler technology, offers a compelling cost-of-ownership advantage versus silver-filled formulas, delivering thermal conductivity exceeding 300 W/m-K, reduced pressure (10-15 MPas) and temperature requirements (200° C – 250° C) for lower die stress, and faster processing time to accommodate mass production. The new pressure-assisted sintering formula is especially well-suited for current and next-generation SiC applications like power modules, ensuring high reliability and performance comparable to silver-based sintering solutions without the risk of die or substrate damage from the pressure and temperature required with other materials to achieve complete sintering.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;As WBG semiconductors evolve, higher-performance, cost-effective sintering materials that can enable current and next-generation devices with high thermal and electrical capability, as well as more delicate processing parameters to mitigate potential device damage and preserve high yields, will help close the price-performance gap. New copper sintering formulations have the potential to leapfrog silver-based materials and offer manufacturers an innovative, competitive, sustainable, and cost-efficient advantage that can deliver the long-term reliability and exceptional performance necessary for the power sector.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.3dincites.com/2025/12/is-copper-sintering-the-key-to-advancing-wide-band-gap-semiconductors/&quot;&gt;Is Copper Sintering the Key to Advancing Wide Band Gap Semiconductors?&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.3dincites.com&quot;&gt;3D InCites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.3dincites.com/2025/12/is-copper-sintering-the-key-to-advancing-wide-band-gap-semiconductors/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:04:55 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Sequoia-Led Funding Vaults AI Startup Fal to $4.5 Billion Valuation</title>
      <link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-09/sequoia-led-funding-vaults-ai-startup-fal-to-4-5-billion-valuation</link>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence startup Fal raised fresh funding from investors in a deal that values the company at $4.5 billion, according to a person familiar with the matter — triple its valuation from a few months earlier.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-09/sequoia-led-funding-vaults-ai-startup-fal-to-4-5-billion-valuation</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:00:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>