<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Recap News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:30:48 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
    <atom:link href="https://raw.githack.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS/main/Semiconductor-RSS.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <item>
      <title>RAM price hikes: the latest on the global memory shortage</title>
      <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/839353/pc-ram-shortage-pricing-spike-news</link>
      <description> 
 
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/12/STKS523_RAM_SHORTAGE_C.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;crop=0,0,100,100&quot;&gt; 
	 
		 
 
&lt;p&gt;Random access memory, or RAM, is in just about every piece of technology we use. But it’s also the technology that AI companies like OpenAI, Anthropic, Google, and Meta are using to power the servers in their massive data centers. Now, the world’s biggest memory makers — Samsung, SK Hynix, and Micron — are taking advantage of a surge in demand, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/837594/crucial-ram-ssd-micron-ai&quot;&gt;shifting their resources away&lt;/a&gt; from consumer-focused products and toward more lucrative deals with AI companies.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
&lt;p&gt;The result is a severe shortage in RAM for consumer products, which is not only contributing to price hikes on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/828337/ram-memory-shortage-crunch-market-prices-central-micro-center&quot;&gt;RAM kits used by PC builders&lt;/a&gt; but also for the manufacturers of a range of devices, including laptops, smartphones, gaming consoles, and a whole lot more. Some companies, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/836221/raspberry-pi-price-increases-ram-costs&quot;&gt;like Raspberry Pi&lt;/a&gt;, have already raised the prices of their products as a result of the increase, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/831032/cyberpowerpc-maingear-ram-price-increases-pc-gaming&quot;&gt;while others anticipate&lt;/a&gt; price hikes coming soon.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
&lt;p&gt;Here’s all the latest news on the rising price of RAM.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt; 
					&lt;li&gt; 
				&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/837594/crucial-ram-ssd-micron-ai&quot;&gt;Crucial is shutting down — because Micron wants to sell its RAM and SSDs to AI companies instead&lt;/a&gt; 
			&lt;/li&gt; 
					&lt;li&gt; 
				&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/836221/raspberry-pi-price-increases-ram-costs&quot;&gt;DRAM it! Raspberry Pi raises prices&lt;/a&gt; 
			&lt;/li&gt; 
					&lt;li&gt; 
				&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/831032/cyberpowerpc-maingear-ram-price-increases-pc-gaming&quot;&gt;These prebuilt PCs are about to cost more due to rising RAM prices&lt;/a&gt; 
			&lt;/li&gt; 
					&lt;li&gt; 
				&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/828337/ram-memory-shortage-crunch-market-prices-central-micro-center&quot;&gt;RAM prices are so out of control that stores are selling it like lobster&lt;/a&gt; 
			&lt;/li&gt; 
			&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theverge.com/news/839353/pc-ram-shortage-pricing-spike-news</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:28:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>The Trillion-Dollar Race to Fragment the Nvidia Monopoly</title>
      <link>https://www.eetimes.com/the-trillion-dollar-race-to-fragment-the-nvidia-monopoly/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past ten years, Nvidia has dominated the market for advanced computer chips used in machine learning and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Driven by its proprietary CUDA software and rapid innovation, Nvidia&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.eetimes.com/the-trillion-dollar-race-to-fragment-the-nvidia-monopoly/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:23:53 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Data center construction moratorium is gaining steam</title>
      <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/840883/data-center-moratorium-letter-congress</link>
      <description> 
 
&lt;img alt=&quot;An aerial view of a still largely empty data center construction site.&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/12/gettyimages-2243425661.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;crop=0,0,100,100&quot;&gt; 
	 
	A Microsoft data center under construction in Aldie, Virginia, US, on Tuesday, Oct. 28, 2025. | Photo: Getty Images	 
 
&lt;p&gt;More than 230 groups including Food &amp;amp; Water Watch, Physicians for Social Responsibility, and Greenpeace are demanding a pause on the construction of any new data centers in the US until stronger regulations are in place to prevent soaring electricity rates, water use, and pollution.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The rapid, largely unregulated rise of data centers to fuel the AI and crypto frenzy is disrupting communities across the country and threatening Americans&apos; economic, environmental, climate and water security,&quot; the groups say in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foodandwaterwatch.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/National-Data-Center-Moratorium.pdf&quot;&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; sent to Congress on Monday.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;More communities are finding success in their efforts to block data center construction, with an …&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/840883/data-center-moratorium-letter-congress&quot;&gt;Read the full story at The Verge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.theverge.com/news/840883/data-center-moratorium-letter-congress</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:09:24 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Virtual Power Plants Are Finally Having Their Moment</title>
      <link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/virtual-power-plants-battery-tech</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/exterior-of-a-house-with-multiple-roof-top-solar-panels.jpg?id=62288939&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C187%2C0%2C188&quot; alt=&quot;exterior-of-a-house-with-multiple-roof-t&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;German utility RWE implemented the &lt;a href=&quot;https://uplight.com/blog/what-is-virtual-power-plant/&quot;&gt;first known virtual power plant&lt;/a&gt; (VPP) in 2008, aggregating nine small hydroelectric plants for a total capacity of 8.6 megawatts. In general, a VPP pulls together many small components—like rooftop solar, home batteries, and smart thermostats—into a single coordinated power system. The system responds to grid needs on demand, whether by making stored energy available or reducing energy consumption by smart devices during peak hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;VPPs &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/virtual-power-plants-real-power&quot;&gt;had a moment&lt;/a&gt; in the mid-2010s, but market conditions and the technology weren’t quite aligned for them to take off. Electricity demand &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.php?id=65264&quot;&gt;wasn’t high enough&lt;/a&gt;, and existing sources—coal, natural gas, nuclear, and renewables—met demand and kept prices stable. Additionally, despite the costs of hardware like solar panels and batteries falling, the software to link and manage these resources lagged behind, and there wasn’t much financial incentive for it to catch up. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But times have changed, and less than a decade later, the stars are aligning in VPPs’ favor. They’re hitting a deployment inflection point, and they could play a significant role in meeting energy demand over the next 5 to 10 years in a way that’s faster, cheaper, and greener than other solutions. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;U.S. Electricity Demand Is Growing&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Electricity demand in the United States is expected to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.icf.com/insights/energy/electricity-demand-expected-to-grow&quot;&gt;grow 25 percent&lt;/a&gt; by 2030 due to data center buildouts, electric vehicles, manufacturing, and electrification, according to estimates from technology consultant ICF International.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the same time, a host of bottlenecks are making it hard to expand the grid. There’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/ai-data-centers&quot;&gt;backlog of at least&lt;/a&gt; three to five years on new gas turbines. Hundreds of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.canarymedia.com/articles/transmission/chart-the-us-clean-energy-backlog-is-getting-bigger-and-bigger&quot;&gt;gigawatts of renewables&lt;/a&gt; are languishing in interconnection queues, where there’s also a backlog of up to five years. On the delivery side, there’s a &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/transformer-shortage&quot;&gt;transformer shortage&lt;/a&gt; that could take up to five years to resolve, and a dearth of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cleanenergygrid.org/new-report-reveals-u-s-transmission-buildout-lagging-far-behind-national-needs&quot;&gt;transmission lines&lt;/a&gt;. This all adds up to a long, slow process to add generation and delivery capacity, and it’s not getting faster anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; “Fueling electric vehicles, electric heat, and data centers solely from traditional approaches would increase rates that are already too high,” says &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/brad-heavner-9a63b311/&quot;&gt;Brad Heavner&lt;/a&gt;, the executive director of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://calssa.org/&quot;&gt;California Solar &amp;amp; Storage Association&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Enter the vast network of resources that are already active and grid-connected—and the perfect storm of factors that make now the time to scale them. &lt;a href=&quot;https://sc.edu/study/colleges_schools/engineering_and_computing/faculty-staff/nasiri_adel.php&quot;&gt;Adel Nasiri&lt;/a&gt;, a professor of electrical engineering at the University of South Carolina, says variability of loads from data centers and electric vehicles has increased, as has deployment of grid-scale batteries and storage. There are more distributed energy resources available than there were before, and the last decade has seen advances in grid management using autonomous controls.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the heart of it all, though, is the technology that stores and dispatches electricity on demand: batteries. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Advances in Battery Technology&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the last 10 years, battery prices have plummeted: the average &lt;a href=&quot;https://about.bnef.com/insights/commodities/lithium-ion-battery-pack-prices-see-largest-drop-since-2017-falling-to-115-per-kilowatt-hour-bloombergnef/&quot;&gt;lithium-ion battery pack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://about.bnef.com/insights/commodities/lithium-ion-battery-pack-prices-see-largest-drop-since-2017-falling-to-115-per-kilowatt-hour-bloombergnef/&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://about.bnef.com/insights/commodities/lithium-ion-battery-pack-prices-see-largest-drop-since-2017-falling-to-115-per-kilowatt-hour-bloombergnef/&quot;&gt; price&lt;/a&gt; fell from US $715 per kilowatt-hour in 2014 to $115 per kWh in 2024. Their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.energy.gov/eere/vehicles/articles/fotw-1234-april-18-2022-volumetric-energy-density-lithium-ion-batteries&quot;&gt;energy density&lt;/a&gt; has simultaneously increased thanks to a combination of materials advancements, design optimization of battery cells, and improvements in the packaging of battery systems, says &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/oliver-gross-b4a86714/&quot;&gt;Oliver Gross&lt;/a&gt;, a senior fellow in energy storage and electrification at automaker Stellantis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The biggest improvements have come in batteries’ cathodes and electrolytes, with nickel-based cathodes starting to be used about a decade ago. “In many ways, the cathode limits the capacity of the battery, so by unlocking higher capacity cathode materials, we have been able to take advantage of the intrinsic higher capacity of anode materials,” says &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/gregless/&quot;&gt;Greg Less&lt;/a&gt;, the director of the University of Michigan’s Battery Lab.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Increasing the percentage of nickel in the cathode (relative to other metals) increases energy density because nickel can hold more lithium per gram than materials like cobalt or manganese, exchanging more electrons and participating more fully in the redox reactions that move lithium in and out of the battery. The same goes for silicon, which has become more common in anodes. However, there’s a trade-off: These materials cause more structural instability during the battery’s cycling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The anode and cathode are surrounded by a liquid electrolyte. The electrolyte has to be electrically and chemically stable when exposed to the anode and cathode in order to avoid safety hazards like thermal runaway or fires and rapid degradation. “The real revolution has been the breakthroughs in chemistry to make the electrolyte stable against more reactive cathode materials to get the energy density up,” says Gross. Chemical compound additives—many of them based on sulfur and boron chemistry—for the electrolyte help create stable layers between it and the anode and cathode materials. “They form these protective layers very early in the manufacturing process so that the cell stays stable throughout its life.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These advances have primarily been made on electric vehicle batteries, which differ from grid-scale batteries in that EVs are often parked or idle, while grid batteries are constantly connected and need to be ready to transfer energy. However, Gross says, “the same approaches that got our energy density higher in EVs can also be applied to optimizing grid storage. The materials might be a little different, but the methodologies are the same.” The most popular cathode material for grid storage batteries at the moment is lithium iron phosphate, or LFP.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks to these technical gains and dropping costs, a domino effect has been set in motion: The more batteries deployed, the cheaper they become, which fuels more deployment and creates positive feedback loops.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regions that have experienced frequent blackouts—like parts of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.texastribune.org/2024/07/18/texas-energy-grid-power-outages-climate-change-infrastructure/&quot;&gt;Texas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.latimes.com/environment/story/2025-11-06/edison-blacks-out-more-customers-to-stop-utility-sparked-fires&quot;&gt;California&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/puerto-rico-earthquake-power-outages-prepa-news&quot;&gt;Puerto Rico&lt;/a&gt;—are a prime market for home batteries. Texas-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.basepowercompany.com/&quot;&gt;Base Power&lt;/a&gt;, which raised $1 billion in Series C funding in October, installs batteries at customers’ homes and becomes their retail power provider, charging the batteries when excess wind or solar production makes prices cheap, and then selling that energy back to the grid when demand spikes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is, however, still room for improvement. For wider adoption, says Nasiri, “the installed battery cost needs to get under $100 per kWh for large VPP deployments.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Improvements in VPP Software&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The software infrastructure that once limited VPPs to pilot projects has matured into a robust digital backbone, making it feasible to operate VPPs at grid scale. Advances in AI are key: Many VPPs now use machine learning algorithms to predict load flexibility, solar and battery output, customer behavior, and grid stress events. This improves the dependability of a VPP’s capacity, which was historically a major concern for grid operators.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;float:left;&quot;&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;Close-up of a roof-top solar panel.&quot; src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/close-up-of-a-roof-top-solar-panel.jpg?id=62288941&amp;amp;width=980&quot;&gt; &lt;small&gt;While solar panels have advanced, VPPs have been held back by a lack of similar advancement in the needed software until recently.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;small&gt;Sunrun&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity and interoperability standards are still evolving. Interconnection processes and data visibility in many areas aren’t consistent, making it hard to monitor and coordinate distributed resources effectively. In short, while the technology and economics for VPPs are firmly in place, there’s work yet to be done aligning regulation, infrastructure, and market design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On top of technical and cost constraints, VPPs have long been held back by regulations that prevented them from participating in energy markets like traditional generators. SolarEdge recently &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20251029315871/en/SolarEdge-Surpasses-500-MWh-of-Storage-in-Virtual-Power-Plants-Across-16-U.S.-States-Canada-and-Puerto-Rico&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt; enrollment of more than 500 megawatt-hours of residential battery storage in its VPP programs. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/tamarasinensky/&quot;&gt;Tamara Sinensky&lt;/a&gt;, the company’s senior manager of grid services, says the biggest hurdle to achieving this milestone wasn’t technical—it was regulatory program design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;California’s Demand Side Grid Support (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.energy.ca.gov/programs-and-topics/programs/demand-side-grid-support-program&quot;&gt;DSGS&lt;/a&gt;) program, launched in mid-2022, pays homes, businesses, and VPPs to reduce electricity use or discharge energy during grid emergencies. “We’ve seen a massive increase in our VPP enrollments primarily driven by the DSGS program,” says Sinensky. Similarly, Sunrun’s Northern California VPP delivered 535 megawatts of power from home-based batteries to the grid in July, and saw a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.utilitydive.com/news/sunrun-sees-400-growth-in-virtual-power-plant-participation/805169/&quot;&gt;400 percent increase&lt;/a&gt; in VPP participation from last year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ferc.gov/ferc-order-no-2222-explainer-facilitating-participation-electricity-markets-distributed-energy&quot;&gt;FERC Order 2222&lt;/a&gt;, issued in 2020, requires regional grid operators to allow VPPs to sell power, reduce load, or provide grid services directly to wholesale market operators, and get paid the same market price as a traditional power plant for those services. However, many states and grid regions don’t yet have a process in place to comply with the FERC order. And because utilities profit from grid expansion and not VPP deployment, they’re not incentivized to integrate VPPs into their operations. Utilities “view customer batteries as competition,” says Heavner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Nasiri, VPPs would have a meaningful impact on the grid if they achieve a penetration of 2 percent of the market’s peak power. “Larger penetration of up to 5 percent for up to 4 hours is required to have a meaningful capacity impact for grid planning and operation,” he says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In other words, VPP operators have their work cut out for them in continuing to unlock the flexible capacity in homes, businesses, and EVs. Additional technical and policy advances could move VPPs from a niche reliability tool to a key power source and grid stabilizer for the energy tumult ahead.&lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/#_msocom_2&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://spectrum.ieee.org/virtual-power-plants-battery-tech</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:07:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Why the Most “Accurate” Glucose Monitors Are Failing Some Users</title>
      <link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/glucose-monitor-accuracy-user-concerns</link>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/media-library/illustration-of-an-arm-with-a-glucose-monitor-against-a-glitchy-line-graph-of-blood-sugar-data.jpg?id=62295175&amp;amp;width=1245&amp;amp;height=700&amp;amp;coordinates=0%2C62%2C0%2C63&quot; alt=&quot;illustration-of-an-arm-with-a-glucose-mo&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Dan Heller received his first batch of Dexcom’s latest &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/why-noviosenses-ineye-glucose-monitor-might-work-better-than-googles&quot;&gt;continuous glucose monitors&lt;/a&gt; in early 2023, he decided to run a small experiment: He wore the new biosensor and the previous generation at the same time to see how they compared in measuring his glucose levels. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new, seventh-generation model (aptly called the G7) made by San Diego-based healthcare company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dexcom.com/&quot;&gt;Dexcom&lt;/a&gt; had just begun shipping in the United States. Dexcom claimed the G7 to be the &lt;a href=&quot;https://investors.dexcom.com/news/news-details/2022/Dexcom-G7-Receives-FDA-Clearance-The-Most-Accurate-Continuous-Glucose-Monitoring-System-Cleared-in-the-U.S/default.aspx&quot;&gt;“most accurate sensor”&lt;/a&gt; available to the thousands of people with Type 1 diabetes who use continuous glucose monitors to help manage their blood sugars. But Heller found that its real-world performance wasn’t up to par. In a September 2023 post on his Substack, which is dedicated to covering Type 1 diabetes research and management, he &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.substack.com/pub/danheller/p/the-dexcom-g7-vs-g6-which-is-better?r=1q2796&amp;amp;utm_campaign=post&amp;amp;utm_medium=web&quot;&gt;wrote about the experience&lt;/a&gt; and predicted an increase in adverse events with the G7, drawing on his past experience leading tech and biotech companies. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the two years since Heller’s experiment, many other users have reported issues with the device. Some complaints regard failed connection and deployment issues, which Dexcom claims to have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.medtechdive.com/news/dexcom-execs-fixed-g7-quality-problems/804383/&quot;&gt;now addressed&lt;/a&gt;. More concerning are reports of erratic, inaccurate readings. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/1539517486772872&quot;&gt;public Facebook group&lt;/a&gt; dedicated to sharing negative experiences with the G7 has grown to thousands of users, and several class action &lt;a href=&quot;https://rosenlegal.com/case/dexcom-inc/&quot;&gt;lawsuits&lt;/a&gt; have been filed against the company, alleging &lt;a href=&quot;https://wilshirelawfirm.com/dexcom-class-action-lawsuit/&quot;&gt;false advertising&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://cowperlaw.com/cowper-law-llp-dicello-levitt-file-class-action-against-dexcom-over-misleading-claims-about-g7-cgm/&quot;&gt;misleading claims&lt;/a&gt; about device accuracy. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet, based on a standard metric in the industry, the G7 is one of the most accurate glucose sensors available. “Accuracy in the performance of our device is our number one priority. We understand this is a lifesaving device for people with Type 1 diabetes,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/peter-c-simpson-533a083/&quot;&gt;Peter Simpson&lt;/a&gt;, Dexcom’s senior vice president of innovation and sensor technology, told &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;IEEE Spectrum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. Simpson acknowledged some variability in individual sensors, but stood by the accuracy of the devices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So why have users faced issues? In part, metrics used in marketing can be misleading compared to real world performance. Differences in study design, combined with complex biological realities, mean that the accuracy of these biosensors can’t be boiled down to one number—and users are learning this the hard way. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Dexcom’s Glucose Monitors&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuous glucose monitors (CGMs) typically consist of a small filament inserted under the skin, a transmitter, and a receiver. The filament is coated with an enzyme that generates an electrical signal when it reacts with glucose in the fluid surrounding the body’s cells. That signal is then converted to a digital signal and processed to generate glucose readings every few minutes. Each sensor lasts a week or two before needing to be replaced. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The technology has come a long way in recent years. In the 2010s, these devices required blood glucose calibrations twice a day and still weren’t reliable enough to dose insulin based on the readings. Now, some insulin pumps use the near-real-time data to &lt;a href=&quot;https://spectrum.ieee.org/artificial-pancreas-could-conquer-diabetes&quot;&gt;automatically make adjustments&lt;/a&gt;. With those improvements has come greater trust in the data users receive—and higher standards. A faulty reading could result in a dangerous dose of insulin. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The G7 introduced several changes to Dexcom’s earlier designs, including a much smaller footprint, and updated the algorithm used to translate sensor signals into glucose readings for better accuracy, Simpson says. “From a performance perspective, we did demonstrate in a clinical trial that the G7 is significantly more accurate than the G6,” he says. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So Heller and others were surprised when the new Dexcom sensor seemed to be performing worse. For some batches of sensors, it’s possible that the issue was in part due to an unvalidated change in a component used in a resistive layer of the sensors. The new component showed worse performance, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fda.gov/inspections-compliance-enforcement-and-criminal-investigations/warning-letters/dexcom-inc-700835-03042025&quot;&gt;warning letter&lt;/a&gt; issued by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration in March 2025, following an audit of two U.S. manufacturing sites. The material has since been removed from all G7 sensors, Simpson says, and the company is continuing to work with the FDA to address concerns. (“The warning letter does not restrict Dexcom’s ability to produce, market, manufacture or distribute products, require recall of any products, nor restrict our ability to seek clearance of new products,” Dexcom added in a statement.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“&lt;span&gt;There is a distribution of accuracies that have to do with people’s physiology and also the devices themselves. Even in our clinical studies, we saw some that were really precise and some that had a little bit of inaccuracy to them,” says Simpson. “But in general, our sensor is very accurate.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In late November Abbott—one of Dexcom’s main competitors—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fda.gov/medical-devices/medical-device-recalls-and-early-alerts/early-alert-glucose-monitor-sensor-issue-abbott-diabetes-care&quot;&gt;recalled some of its CGMs&lt;/a&gt; due to inaccurate low glucose readings. The recall affects approximately 3 million sensors and was caused by an issue with one of Abbott’s production lines. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The discrepancy between reported accuracy and user experience, however, goes beyond any one company’s manufacturing missteps. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Does MARD Matter? &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The accuracy of CGM systems is frequently measured via “mean absolute relative difference,” or MARD, a percentage that compares the sensor readings to laboratory blood glucose measurements. The lower the MARD, the more accurate the sensor. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This number is often used in advertising and marketing, and it has a historical relevance, says &lt;a href=&quot;https://de.linkedin.com/in/manueich/de&quot;&gt;Manuel Eichenlaub&lt;/a&gt;, a biomedical engineer at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ifdt-ulm.de/en/&quot;&gt;Institute for Diabetes Technology Ulm&lt;/a&gt; in Germany, where he and his colleagues conduct independent CGM performance studies. For years, there was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.liebertpub.com/doi/10.1089/dia.2023.0435&quot;&gt;a general belief&lt;/a&gt; that a MARD under 10 percent meant a system would be accurate enough to be used for insulin dosing. In 2018, the FDA established a specific set of accuracy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ecfr.gov/current/title-21/chapter-I/subchapter-H/part-862/subpart-B/section-862.1355&quot;&gt;requirements&lt;/a&gt; beyond MARD for insulin-guiding glucose monitors, including Dexcom’s. But manufacturers design the clinical trials that determine accuracy metrics, and the way studies are designed can make a big difference. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For instance, blood glucose levels serve as the “ground truth to compare the CGM values against,” says Eichenlaub. But glucose levels vary across blood compartments in the body; blood collected from capillaries with a finger prick fluctuates more and can have glucose levels around 5 to 10 percent higher than venous blood. (Dexcom tests against a gold-standard venous blood analyzer. When users see inaccuracies against home meters that use capillary blood, it could in part be a reflection of the meter’s own inaccuracy, Simpson says, though he acknowledges real inaccuracies in CGMs as well.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the distribution of sampling isn’t standardized. CGMs are known to be less accurate at the beginning and end of use, or when glucose levels are out of range or changing quickly. That means measured accuracy could be skewed by taking fewer samples right after a meal or late in the CGM’s lifetime. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Simpson, Dexcom’s trial protocol meets the FDA’s expectation and tests the devices in different blood sugar ranges across the life of the sensor. “Within these clinical trials, we do stress the sensors to try and simulate those real world conditions,” he says. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dexcom and other companies advertise a MARD around 8 percent. But some independent studies are more demanding and find higher numbers; a &lt;a href=&quot;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.1177/19322968251315459&quot;&gt;head-to-head study of three popular CGMs&lt;/a&gt; that Eichenlaub led found MARD values closer to 10 percent or higher.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Eichenlaub and other CGM experts believe that more standardization of testing and an extension of the FDA requirements are necessary, so they &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0009898125006072&quot;&gt;recently proposed comprehensive guidelines&lt;/a&gt; on CGM performance testing. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;In the United States and Europe&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, a few manufacturers currently dominate the market. But&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; newer players are entering the growing market and, especially in Europe,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; may not meet the same standards as legacy manufacturers, he says&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;. “Having a standardized way of evaluating the performance of those systems is very important.”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For users like Heller though, better accuracy only matters if it yields better diabetes management. “I don’t care about MARD. I want data that is reliably &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;actionable&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;,” Heller says. He encourages engineers working on these devices to think like the patient. “At some point, there’s quantitative data, but you need qualitative data.” &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://spectrum.ieee.org/glucose-monitor-accuracy-user-concerns</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 18:07:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>