<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Recap News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 20:00:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
    <atom:link href="https://raw.githack.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS/main/Semiconductor-RSS.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <item>
      <title>Artificial photosynthesis catalyst converts carbon dioxide into fuel using sunlight</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-12-artificial-photosynthesis-catalyst-carbon-dioxide.html</link>
      <description>A joint research team has developed a highly efficient photocatalyst that can convert carbon dioxide into the high-value-added fuel, methane, using sunlight, while explaining its operating principles. The work is published in the journal ACS Catalysis.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://phys.org/news/2025-12-artificial-photosynthesis-catalyst-carbon-dioxide.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:58:10 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Durable catalyst shields itself for affordable green hydrogen production</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-12-durable-catalyst-shields-green-hydrogen.html</link>
      <description>An international research team led by Professor Philip C.Y. Chow at The University of Hong Kong (HKU) has unveiled a new catalyst that overcomes a major challenge in producing green hydrogen at scale. This innovation makes the process of producing oxygen efficiently and reliably in the harsh acidic environment used by today&apos;s most promising industrial electrolyzers.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://phys.org/news/2025-12-durable-catalyst-shields-green-hydrogen.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:47:41 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Trump blessing Nvidia AI chip sales to China gets chilly reception from GOP</title>
      <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2025/12/09/trump-nvidia-china-ai-chips-gop-congress.html</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/108139104-1746048626472-gettyimages-2212178893-AFP_444Y2UG.jpeg?v=1765299307&amp;amp;w=1920&amp;amp;h=1080&quot; alt=&quot;108139104-1746048626472-gettyimages-2212&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Trump said Chinese President Xi Jinping &quot;responded positively&quot; to the proposal to let Nvidia sell H200 AI chips on condition that the U.S. gets 25% of revenue.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.cnbc.com/2025/12/09/trump-nvidia-china-ai-chips-gop-congress.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:44:16 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>HW Security: Inner Product Masking With Fault Detection Via ISE (KU Leuven, NUS, Rambus)</title>
      <link>https://semiengineering.com/hw-security-inner-product-masking-with-fault-detection-via-ise-ku-leuven-nus-rambus/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/Black-White-lock-01-21-21AdobeStock_216445859-scaled.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Black-White-lock-01-21-21AdobeStock_2164&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new technical paper titled “Extending and Accelerating Inner Product Masking with Fault Detection via Instruction Set Extension” was published by researchers at KU Leuven, National University of Singapore, and Rambus.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;“Inner product masking is a well-studied masking countermeasure against side-channel attacks. IPM-FD further extends the IPM scheme with fault detection capabilities. However, implementing IPM-FD in software especially on embedded devices results in high computational overhead. Therefore, in this work we perform a detailed analysis of all building blocks for IPMFD scheme and propose a Masked Processing Unit to accelerate all operations, for example multiplication and IPM-FD specific Homogenization. We can then offload these computational extensive operations with dedicated hardware support. With only 4.05% and 4.01% increase in Look-Up Tables and Flip-Flops (Random Number Generator excluded), respectively, compared with baseline cv32e40p RISC-V core, we can achieve up to 16.55× speed-up factor with optimal configuration. We then practically evaluate the side-channel security via uni- and bivariate Test Vector Leakage Assessment which exhibits no leakage. Finally, we use two different methods to simulate the injected fault and confirm the fault detection capability of up to &lt;i&gt;k&lt;/i&gt; − 1 faults, with &lt;i&gt;k&lt;/i&gt; being the replication factor.”&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;Find the &lt;a href=&quot;https://eprint.iacr.org/2025/2165&quot;&gt;technical paper here&lt;/a&gt;. December 2025.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;Cui, Songqiao, Geng Luo, Junhan Bao, Josep Balasch, and Ingrid Verbauwhede. “Extending and Accelerating Inner Product Masking with Fault Detection via Instruction Set Extension.” Cryptology ePrint Archive (2025).&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://semiengineering.com/hw-security-inner-product-masking-with-fault-detection-via-ise-ku-leuven-nus-rambus/&quot;&gt;HW Security: Inner Product Masking With Fault Detection Via ISE (KU Leuven, NUS, Rambus)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://semiengineering.com&quot;&gt;Semiconductor Engineering&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://semiengineering.com/hw-security-inner-product-masking-with-fault-detection-via-ise-ku-leuven-nus-rambus/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 19:38:30 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>