<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Recap News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:00:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <!-- ADD THIS LINE BELOW -->
  <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
  <!-- KEEP THIS LINE (Self Link) -->
  <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS/refs/heads/main/Semiconductor-RSS.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <item>
      <title>Meta will let Facebook and Instagram users in the EU share less data</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/social-media/meta-will-let-facebook-and-instagram-users-in-the-eu-share-less-data-183535897.html?src=rss</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meta will soon allow Facebook and Instagram users in the European Union to choose to share less data and see less personalized ads on the platform, the European Commission &lt;a href=&quot;https://digital-markets-act.ec.europa.eu/meta-commits-give-eu-users-choice-personalised-ads-under-dma-2025-12-08_en&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt;. The change will begin to roll out in January, according to the regulator. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;This is the first time that such a choice is offered on Meta&apos;s social networks,&quot; the commission said in a statement. &quot;Meta will give users the effective choice between: consenting to share all their data and seeing fully personalised advertising, and opting to share less personal data for an experience with more limited personalised advertising.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The move from Meta comes after the European Commission had fined the company €200 million over its ad-free subscription plans in the EU, which the regulator deemed &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/eu-criticizes-metas-privacy-for-cash-business-model-103042528.html&quot;&gt;consent or pay&lt;/a&gt;.&quot; Meta began offering ad-free subscriptions to EU users &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/facebook-and-instagram-will-start-offering-ad-free-plans-in-europe-in-november-141650104.html&quot;&gt;in 2023&lt;/a&gt;, and later &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/meta-cuts-the-price-of-its-ad-free-plan-by-40-percent-in-a-bid-to-sate-eu-regulators-174926790.html&quot;&gt;lowered the price&lt;/a&gt; of the plans in response to criticism from the commission. Those plans haven&apos;t been very popular, however, with one Meta executive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/what-weve-learned-from-ftc-v-meta-antitrust-trial-162048138.html&quot;&gt;admitting&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year that there&apos;s been &quot;very little interest&quot; from users. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a statement, a Meta spokesperson said that &quot;we acknowledge&quot; the European Commission&apos;s statement. &quot;Personalized ads are vital for Europe’s economy — last year, Meta’s ads were linked to €213 billion in economic activity and supported 1.44 million jobs across the EU.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/social-media/meta-will-let-facebook-and-instagram-users-in-the-eu-share-less-data-183535897.html?src=rss</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:47:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>