<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Recap News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 07:30:30 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
    <atom:link href="https://raw.githack.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS/main/Semiconductor-RSS.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <item>
      <title>Strong Momentum expected for Data Center AI Chip Packaging in 2025-2030</title>
      <link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/strong-momentum-expected-for-data-center-ai-chip-packaging-in-2025-2030-302636228.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;TAIPEI&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Dec. 9, 2025&lt;/span&gt; /PRNewswire/ -- &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data Center AI Chip Shipments Continue to Grow&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/#continue-jump&quot;&gt;Continue Reading &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/#&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Credit: Digitimes&quot; src=&quot;https://mma.prnewswire.com/media/2841330/2.jpg?w=350&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt;  Credit: Digitimes    &lt;div&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/#&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Credit: Digitimes&quot; src=&quot;https://mma.prnewswire.com/media/2841328/Credit_Digitimes.jpg?w=350&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt;  Credit: Digitimes    &lt;div&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/#&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Credit: Digitimes&quot; src=&quot;https://mma.prnewswire.com/media/2841329/Credit_Digitimes.jpg?w=350&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt;  Credit: Digitimes   &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;According to the latest report published by &lt;b&gt;DIGITIMES Asia&lt;/b&gt;, global data center AI chip shipments are projected to grow from &lt;b&gt;30.5 million units&lt;/b&gt; in 2024 to &lt;b&gt;53.4 million units&lt;/b&gt; in 2030. This data center AI chip category includes high-end and mid-range GPUs, application-specific AI chips (such as Google&apos;s TPUs), AI server CPUs, and networking/interconnect-related chips (e.g., Switch ASICs/rack-scale-up Interconnect Chips/DPUs &amp;amp; NICs).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In terms of growth rate, the fastest-growing segments by shipment volume include application-specific AI chips, mid-range GPUs that use&lt;b&gt; GDDR DRAM&lt;/b&gt; (such as Nvidia CPX GPUs), and &lt;b&gt;interconnect-related chips&lt;/b&gt;, such as NVSwitch ICs. Among these five chip categories, the shipment volume growth rates for &lt;b&gt;high-end GPUs&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;AI server CPUs&lt;/b&gt; are relatively lower over the 2024–2030 period, with a Compound Annual Growth Rate (CAGR) of only about &lt;b&gt;10%&lt;/b&gt;. However, when considering the revenue from high-end packaging and end-market sales, the growth rate will be much higher than the shipment growth rate. The main reasons for this include the increased &lt;b&gt;content value per chip&lt;/b&gt; and the adoption of &lt;b&gt;advanced packaging&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, AMD recently forecast that the global server CPU revenue Total Addressable Market (TAM) CAGR will reach &lt;b&gt;18%&lt;/b&gt; between 2025 and 2030 (implying that the Average Selling Price CAGR for server CPUs could exceed 7% due to the jump in core count and the adoption of more advanced processes and packaging). For GPUs, despite relatively moderate growth in shipments, wafer foundry and packaging revenue CAGRs are both expected to exceed 40% in 2024-2030, driven by the increasing number of GPU and I/O dies per chip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Data Center AI Chip Packaging Revenue Remains Focused on GPUs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, &lt;b&gt;application-specific AI chips&lt;/b&gt; like Google&apos;s TPU and AWS&apos;s Trainium have garnered significant attention for their tailored power-efficiency characteristics, sparking speculation that they might replace GPUs. According to the latest &quot;Global Data Center AI Chip Packaging Market Forecast 2024-2030&quot; report published by DIGITIMES Asia, the overall revenue share of data center AI chip packaging will remain &lt;b&gt;GPU-centric&lt;/b&gt; throughout the 2024–2030 forecast period. It is estimated that by 2030, packaging revenue for data center GPUs will remain &lt;b&gt;over 40% higher&lt;/b&gt; than that of application-specific AI chips.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While AI server CPUs and AI networking-related chips have high shipment volumes, the &lt;b&gt;high-end packaging market&lt;/b&gt; will still be overwhelmingly dominated by &lt;b&gt;GPUs&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;application-specific AI chips&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drivers and Inhibitors for Advanced Packaging of Data Center AI Chips&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;DIGITIMES Asia forecasts that the global market size for &lt;b&gt;advanced packaging of data center AI chips&lt;/b&gt; will grow from &lt;b&gt;US$5.6 billion&lt;/b&gt; in 2024 to &lt;b&gt;US$53.1 billion&lt;/b&gt; in 2030, representing a CAGR of over &lt;b&gt;40%&lt;/b&gt;. This aligns closely with AMD&apos;s recent Financial Analyst Day estimate that the global Data Center TAM CAGR will exceed 40% over the next five years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is a summary of the main drivers and inhibitors for the global market for advanced packaging of data center AI chips:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Key Drivers:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul type=&quot;disc&quot;&gt; &lt;li&gt;The &lt;b&gt;AI wave&lt;/b&gt; and the compute power &lt;b&gt;arms race&lt;/b&gt; among tech giants.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Advanced packaging driving &lt;b&gt;system-level scaling&lt;/b&gt; to extend Moore&apos;s Law.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Geopolitical competition between the U.S. and China, and the rise of &lt;b&gt;Sovereign AI&lt;/b&gt; initiatives.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Key Inhibitors:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul type=&quot;disc&quot;&gt; &lt;li&gt;The re-evaluation of &lt;b&gt;return on investment (ROI)&lt;/b&gt; relative to massive computing power investments.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;The impact of cheaper and more efficient new&lt;b&gt; technologies&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more details on AI Chip, and the future outlook for major AI chip packaging technologies in data centers, check out: &lt;b&gt;AI Chip packaging &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.digitimes.com/reports/ai/2025_ai_chip_packaging&quot;&gt;https://www.digitimes.com/reports/ai/2025_ai_chip_packaging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SOURCE DIGITIMES ASIA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://rt.prnewswire.com/rt.gif?NewsItemId=HK42265&amp;amp;Transmission_Id=202512090138PR_NEWS_USPR_____HK42265&amp;amp;DateId=20251209&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/strong-momentum-expected-for-data-center-ai-chip-packaging-in-2025-2030-302636228.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 07:24:36 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>