<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Professional News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Curated articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 12:11:43 GMT</lastBuildDate>

    <item>
      <title>Skymizerʼs HyperThought™ Wins &quot;Best IP/Processor of the Yearˮ and &quot;Most Promising Productˮ at EE Awards Asia 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/skymizers-hyperthought-wins-best-ipprocessor-of-the-year-and-most-promising-product-at-ee-awards-asia-2025-302634717.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;TAIPEI&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Dec. 6, 2025&lt;/span&gt; /PRNewswire/ -- Skymizer today announced that its next-generation HyperThought™ LLM Accelerator IP has been awarded &quot;&lt;b&gt;Best IP/Processor of the Year&lt;/b&gt;ˮ and named the &quot;&lt;b&gt;Most Promising Product&lt;/b&gt;ˮ at the prestigious EE Awards Asia 2025, hosted by ASPENCORE at the Grand Mayfull Taipei Hotel. The dual recognition marks HyperThought as one of the most forward-looking semiconductor IP breakthroughs in the Asia-Pacific technology landscape.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Now celebrating its 5th anniversary, the EE Awards Asia program honors innovations selected by engineers and industry leaders across the region. HyperThought™ stood out among hundreds of entries spanning processors, SoCs, sensors, wireless ICs, AI solutions, and test equipment—earning top distinction as the yearʼs most transformative semiconductor IP.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;HyperThought™: Accelerating the Future of Agentic, Multimodal SoCs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Skymizerʼs HyperThought™ represents a new class of multimodal, scalable LLM accelerator IP purpose-built for the coming generation of agentic AI workflows, on-device intelligence, and edge-to-cloud hybrid applications.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Unlike conventional NPUs or fixed-function ML accelerators, HyperThought is architected from the ground up for:&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;ul type=&quot;disc&quot;&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Multimodal LLM/VLM Execution&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;Supporting text, vision, speech, and sensor-based AI with unified &lt;span&gt;token&lt;/span&gt; processing.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Agentic Workflow Optimization&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;Accelerating the emerging class of AI agents that require real-time planning, reflection, tool-use, and memory.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Scalable Edge-to-Enterprise Deployment&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;From micro-edge devices and automotive ECUs to humanoid robots, smart cameras,   and industrial IoT gateways.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Superior Performance-per-Watt and SRAM Efficiency&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;Delivering next-generation TTFT, TPS, context window, and latency performance under           strict edge-power envelopes.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Skymizer CMO William Wei: &quot;HyperThought is Built for the Agentic SoC Eraˮ&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;William Wei, Chief Marketing Officer of Skymizer, represented the company at the EE Awards Asia 2025 ceremony and emphasized the strategic significance of this win:&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&quot;HyperThought™ is not just an accelerator IP — it is a foundation for the next decade of agentic intelligence.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;From multimodal LLMs to real-time robotic and automotive agents, the future SoC must run AI that plans, reasons, sees, acts, and interacts. HyperThought was designed precisely for this new era.ˮ&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Wei added that the award validates Skymizerʼs long-term bet on on-device agentic AI, predicting that LLM-centric SoCs will become the defining architecture for mobile, automotive, robotics, and edge computing.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;A Milestone for Skymizer and the Asia Semiconductor Ecosystem&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The EE Awards Asia jury highlighted HyperThought for its:&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;ul type=&quot;disc&quot;&gt; &lt;li&gt;Breakthrough support for multimodal transformer workloads&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;High scalability across process nodes and SoC configurations&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Strong alignment with global trends in on-device LLM inference&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Potential to reshape AI compute in edge, robotics, and smart-device markets&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;HyperThoughtʼs recognition as &quot;Most Promising Productˮ places Skymizer among the leaders defining next-generation AI silicon, with strong interest from ecosystem partners in automotive, robotics, edge AI, and consumer electronics.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Skymizer&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Skymizer is a Taiwan-based AI semiconductor IP company specializing in LLM acceleration, compiler technology, and agentic AI system architectures. Its flagship HyperThought™ IP gives SoC manufacturers the ability to build their own AI-native processors for multimodal LLMs, autonomous agents, and edge intelligence.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;SOURCE Skymizer&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://rt.prnewswire.com/rt.gif?NewsItemId=HK40875&amp;amp;Transmission_Id=202512062353PR_NEWS_USPR_____HK40875&amp;amp;DateId=20251206&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 05:33:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Pat Gelsinger wants to save Moore’s Law, with a little help from the Feds</title>
      <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/12/06/pat-gelsinger-wants-to-save-moores-law-with-a-little-help-from-the-feds/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/54963243726_2bb5c81046_k.jpg?resize=1200,800&quot; alt=&quot;54963243726_2bb5c81046_k.jpg?resize=1200&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;The company is aiming to produce its first silicon wafers by 2028 and have its first commercial system online by 2029.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:22:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>