<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Recap News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 23:00:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
    <atom:link href="https://raw.githack.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS/main/Semiconductor-RSS.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <item>
      <title>Pfeiffer Vacuum+Fab Solutions at SEMICON Europa 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/pfeiffer-vacuumfab-solutions-at-semicon-europa-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pfeiffer-vacuumfab-solutions-at-semicon-europa-2025</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/60ca50fa046b5dfa00dcdbe4afe8721fedbe411069563961be1471aa20e65faf?s=164&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&quot; alt=&quot;60ca50fa046b5dfa00dcdbe4afe8721fedbe4110&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Pfeiffer offers high-quality vacuum solutions for the entire semiconductor fab – from cleanroom to exhaust – optimizing manufacturing processes with precision, reliability, and efficiency. &lt;/span&gt;Visitors came by the booth to discuss the technologies on display as well as developing trends in the semiconductor industry with the experts. Of particular interest was ARGOS, the new predictive maintenance service solution that Pfeiffer introduced for the first time during the trade show.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reduced downtime thanks to digital semiconductor services&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;ARGOS is an on-site machine learning and analytics service for semiconductor fabs that combines production-grade machine learning with decades of vacuum pump and abatement expertise. It converts operational data into prioritized, risk-based actions to increase uptime, reduce total cost-of-ownership, and stabilize yield. This vendor-independent solution operates entirely on the premises, keeping sensitive fab data under customer control.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Vacuum pumps for the semiconductor industry&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;The UltiDry multi-stage roots vacuum pump was another highlight at this year’s booth. &lt;/span&gt;Its oil-free multi-stage compression ensures clean, dry vacuum without contamination, which is crucial for the sensitive processes in the semiconductor industry. With enhanced powder management and the ability to handle high inlet flow and withstand corrosive gases, the UltiDry is &lt;span&gt;well suited for harsh applications. A full-size model was showcased in combination with ARGOS to allow visitors to see how the two pieces of hardware are connected.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Waste gas treatment system &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;Pfeiffer also exhibited the CT-TW-H, a high-temperature thermal-wet gas abatement system. The CT-TW-H combines the wide process coverage of flame abatement with the fuel-free aspects of plasma abatement. The systems feature lower operating costs and secondary emissions and can destroy the molecular process gas NF&lt;span&gt;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/span&gt; at class-leading levels with extremely low NOx emissions. This provides a sustainable solution with a minimal carbon footprint for CVD and metal-etch processes.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;A look inside a semiconductor fab&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;As well as the different technologies presented, a 3D-printed model of a semiconductor fab displayed the setup of a manufacturing facility in a tangible way – from the cleanroom to the sub-fab. Alongside an interactive touch display showing a digital fab, visitors to the booth could explore where each of the various technologies from Pfeiffer are integrated throughout the facility.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/pfeiffer-vacuumfab-solutions-at-semicon-europa-2025/&quot;&gt;Pfeiffer Vacuum+Fab Solutions at SEMICON Europa 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com&quot;&gt;Semiconductor Digest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/pfeiffer-vacuumfab-solutions-at-semicon-europa-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pfeiffer-vacuumfab-solutions-at-semicon-europa-2025</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 22:57:48 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>CAFC Says Design, Development Knowledge Not Sufficiently Defined in Alleged Self-Inflating Tire Trade Secrets</title>
      <link>https://ipwatchdog.com/2025/12/08/cafc-design-development-knowledge-sufficiently-defined-alleged-self-inflating-tire-trade-secrets/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ipwatchdog.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/11/Depositphotos_417844404_XL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Depositphotos_417844404_XL.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit issued a precedential ruling in Coda Development S.R.O. v. Goodyear Tire &amp;amp; Rubber Co. affirming the Northern District of Ohio’s post-verdict grant of judgment as a matter of law (JMOL) to Goodyear on state trade secret and federal inventorship claims raised by Coda. The Federal Circuit ruled that Coda’s trade secret claims were either not defined with sufficient particularity or were publicly disclosed in patent applications filed by Coda, leading the appellate court to dismiss the appellant’s correction of inventorship claims as well.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipwatchdog.com/2025/12/08/cafc-design-development-knowledge-sufficiently-defined-alleged-self-inflating-tire-trade-secrets/&quot;&gt;CAFC Says Design, Development Knowledge Not Sufficiently Defined in Alleged Self-Inflating Tire Trade Secrets&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipwatchdog.com&quot;&gt;IPWatchdog.com | Patents &amp;amp; Intellectual Property Law&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://ipwatchdog.com/2025/12/08/cafc-design-development-knowledge-sufficiently-defined-alleged-self-inflating-tire-trade-secrets/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 22:45:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>SoftBank and Nvidia reportedly in talks to fund SkildAI at $14B, nearly tripling its value</title>
      <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/12/08/softbank-and-nvidia-reportedly-in-talks-to-fund-skildai-at-14b-nearly-tripling-its-value/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/02/GettyImages-ai-generated-3519407f-5502-416b-8a8d-1405b2058c44.jpg?w=1024&quot; alt=&quot;GettyImages-ai-generated-3519407f-5502-4&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Skild AI is developing a hardware-agnostic foundation model for robots that can be customized for various uses.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://techcrunch.com/2025/12/08/softbank-and-nvidia-reportedly-in-talks-to-fund-skildai-at-14b-nearly-tripling-its-value/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 22:40:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>The 2025 MRAM Global Innovation Forum to Showcase MRAM Technology Innovations, Advances, &amp; Research from Industry Experts</title>
      <link>https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/the-2025-mram-global-innovation-forum-to-showcase-mram-technology-innovations-advances-research-from-industry-experts/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-2025-mram-global-innovation-forum-to-showcase-mram-technology-innovations-advances-research-from-industry-experts</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/60ca50fa046b5dfa00dcdbe4afe8721fedbe411069563961be1471aa20e65faf?s=164&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&quot; alt=&quot;60ca50fa046b5dfa00dcdbe4afe8721fedbe4110&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a title=&quot;This external link will open in a new window&quot; href=&quot;https://us.cisionone.cision.com/c/eJwszj2OKyEQBODTQIbF_0BA4GSuYUHT2OgN5i2MZ6-_YrXp162qykE60NxSDGKzRmjrnaevkNE4KcCCByhu_WhuXEaMygiZFK3BemW5MFhkcukhBOTirDcJieazZvxXv1iL9cAxmXWl6FQ22Fhyb-Nu60CP8DrP_5OoO5E7kfusJ87bs_fngTfojcj9qvhN5N5GbKWPz6JXb0gb5hrZwAPjRFZz-IXHHxB1F95yY-kIM8erzrUJW4X-zh84-8j1ifNcJXSeA7GtDGNFlsCBSYuCadCeJb1xpiKgiaCKhEivIH8CAAD__-lvYU8&quot;&gt;MRAM Global Innovation Forum&lt;/a&gt; is the industry’s premier platform for Magnetoresistive Random Access Memory (MRAM) technology, bringing together leading magnetics experts and researchers from industry and academia to share the latest MRAM advancements. Now in its 13th year, the annual one-day conference will be held the day after the IEEE International Electron Devices Meeting (IEDM) on December 11, 2025 from 8:45am to 6pm at the Hilton San Francisco Union Square Hotel’s Imperial Ballroom A/B.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;A type of non-volatile memory, MRAM technology is known for its high speed, endurance, scalability, low power consumption and radiation hardness. Data in MRAM devices is stored by magnetic storage elements instead of an electric charge, in contrast to conventional memory technologies. MRAM technology is increasingly used in embedded memory applications for automotive microcontrollers, edge AI devices, data centers, sensors, aerospace, and in wearable devices.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The 2025 MRAM technical program includes 12 invited presentations from leading global MRAM experts, as well as an evening panel.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;“The STT-MRAM market is growing rapidly now, especially with use of embedded STT-MRAM in next-generation automotive microcontroller units,” said Kevin Garello, MRAM Forum co-chair (since 2021) and senior researcher engineer at SPINTEC. “I expect edge AI applications to be the next big market for STT-MRAM.”&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;“I am pleased to see that over the years, the MRAM Forum series has grown into a landmark event within the MRAM industrial ecosystem,” said Bernard Dieny, former MRAM Forum co-chair (2017–2023), and director of research at SPINTEC. “We are witnessing a steady increase in the adoption of this technology across the microelectronics industry, and the initial concerns associated with this new technology are steadily fading away.”&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;Here are details of the 2025 MRAM Global Innovation Forum technical program:&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Presentations (Invited)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;A series of 12 invited talks by leading industry experts form the technical program at the MRAM Forum, presented consecutively in four technology areas:&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technology Development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;•         High-Performance MRAM for Advancing Automotive Innovation, Allen (Yu-Jen) Wang, TSMC&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;–         STT-MRAM technology delivers the high speed, superior endurance, and high-retention capabilities with scalable, reliable solutions required for evolving for autonomous and software-defined vehicles. Key developments of N16 MRAM include meeting Autograde-1 CFR of &amp;lt;1 ppm, and performance that surpasses other NVMs while achieving high production yields. The work also evaluates emerging N5 MRAM, including Flash-like and RAM-like offerings.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;•         MRAM Macro Design Challenges for Automotive Applications in 22nm-FDSOI Technology, Siddarth Gupta, GlobalFoundries&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;–         MRAM’s expansion into automotive requires robust performance across wide voltage and temperature ranges, with ultra-low error rates, high endurance, long term retention, and immunity to magnetic interference. Compared to embedded Flash, MRAM offers high write speeds that enable rapid over-the-air updates for automotive systems. The work presents GF’s 22nm FDSOI 4MB automotive MRAM, highlighting design advancements tailored for automotive operations and discussing SoC integration challenges.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;•         Recent Advances in Robust and Scalable Embedded MRAM, Jeong-Heon Park, Samsung&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;–         Embedded STT-MRAM scalability and reliability are advancing rapidly, as demonstrated by a logic-compatible 8nm, 128Mb device with a 0.017μm² cell, sub-ppm read- and write-failure rates, with stable operation from –40 to 150°C. In parallel, wafer-level shielding enhances magnetic robustness, integrating a soft magnetic layer in the BEOL process to increase protection against external magnetic fields with efficiency that outperforms conventional package-level methods.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;•         Magnetic Field Immunity Demonstration for STT-MRAM, Kerry Nagel, Everspin&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;–         STT-MRAM is susceptible to external magnetic fields from fixed magnets or high-current lines in industrial and commercial applications. STT-MRAM has significantly higher magnetic field immunity than hard disk drives or Toggle MRAM – used for decades in harsh environments. The work presents a discussion of magnetic fields expected from various inputs, and their impact to use cases, along with a live bit error rate demonstration using a fixed magnet STT-MRAM device.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Product Development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;●       MRAM at the Edge, Thomas Jew, NXP&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;–         MCUs with embedded MRAM are expanding into smart Edge devices. Foundries are extending MRAM beyond 2x technology nodes into 1x and 0x nodes, enabling MRAM/MCU migration into advanced CMOS in high performance compute with low power/energy capabilities in connected applications, including the ultimate Edge devices, Software Defined Vehicles. This talk focuses on MRAM in Zonal Controllers, making it an ideal memory to drive SDVs into reality.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;•  Trends in Embedded MRAM MCUs for Edge AI Applications, Tomoya Saito, Renesas&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;–         AI is transforming every aspect of life and is essential for data centers and embedded systems at the edge. AI enhances industrial applications, smart homes, and safety/security systems, minimizing communication latency and improving real-time performance by processing data locally in embedded systems on MCUs/MPUs. The emergence of TinyML has enabled compact models optimized for limited memory and computing, expanding the adoption of AI into MCU-based systems.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;●        eMRAM for Image Sensor Applications, Masanori Hosomi, Sony&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;–         Limitations of pixel bonding and logic wafers have necessitated the use of DRAM and SRAM to meet sensor functions and area limitations. Reduction of memory macro area is achieved with embedded STT-MRAM at less than one-third of SRAM area with non-volatile characteristics for smart MCUs without external memory. eMRAM has been commercialized in GPS, smart watch and wireless systems, as well as image sensor systems.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;•         MRAM Powered by Numem’s AI Memory Engine – Paving the Way for Low-Power Intelligence Everywhere, Max Simmons, Numem&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;–         As AI expands into autonomous robots, smart devices, and embedded systems, the need for intelligent, ultra-efficient memory is critical. Traditional memory was not designed for the low power, fast response, and small form factors required for edge AI. Numem’s advanced foundry MRAM-based AI Memory Engine redefines memory-compute relationship, delivering high-speed, low-leakage, scalable memory optimized for efficient intelligent edge systems.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tooling&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;•         Tight-pitch MRAM Patterning with Lam IBE System, Xiaoyu Kang, LAM&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;–         MRAM MTJ patterning is inherently challenging, and conventional reactive ion etch produces tapered profile and MgO damage. The Lam Kyber® system is an ion beam etching module that provides integrated etch and encapsulation, featuring broad collimated ion beam that covering the wafer As MRAM scales, ion beam is increasingly shadowed by hard-mask, making it challenging to remove metal residuals to prevent device shorting and retain magnetic properties.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;•         Innovations in Wafer-Level Testing for Modern and Next-Generation MRAM Technologies, Siamak Salimy, HProbe&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;–         MRAM is expanding to MCUs, with current deployment based on Spin Transfer Torque MTJs. Immunity of MRAM devices to external magnetic fields is critical, requiring tests under controlled magnetic excitation during operation. MRAM evolution demands high-speed, robust memory, especially for AI and machine learning. Spin Orbit Torque, cross-point, and Gate-SOT MRAM are emerging to meet these requirements, introducing unique opportunities for wafer-level testing.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploratory Topics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;●       Applications &amp;amp; Performance Goals of MRAM in Defense Applications, Mike Burkland, Raytheon&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;–         In addition to performance considerations for MRAM in defense applications, there are market and business considerations which make up the calculus for adoption. The work presents a brief discussion of the current challenges for transfer into production spintronic-based technologies in the context of non-von Neumann architectures. As well, the maturation of technologies, in general, crossing the “Valley of Death” will be discussed.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;●       Progress &amp;amp; Gaps in Double Spin-torque MTJs for Last Level Cache Applications, Guohan Hu, IBM&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;–         This work includes evaluation of double spin-torque MTJs, demonstrating 25% efficiency improvement compared to single-MTJs. Optimized DS-MTJ stacks with synthetic antiferromagnetic bottom reference layers enable reliable anti-parallel alignment for a 4kbit DS-MTJ array. Switching of 4k devices with 2ns write pulses was demonstrated for the first time. Next is DS-MTJ stacks combining high top reference layer efficiency with high activation energy, steep WER slope and low offset field.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;•         Challenges of CMOS/Spintronics-Hybrid Logic Design for Edge AI Hardware, Takahiro Hanyu, Tohoku University&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;–         In AI hardware, power supply is limited in edge environments. To reduce cloud computing loads, it is necessary to enhance processing capability on the edge side. Spintronics devices feature nonvolatility, fast read/write, and high endurance, capable of replacing RAM and low-power, high-performance VLSI processors in edge AI. Nonvolatile near-memory using embedded MRAM can be stacked on CPUs, reducing distance and control complexity, with power-gating control to reduce power consumption.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panel Session&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;Following the technical presentations there will be a panel discussion on the theme, “MRAM in System-Level Design: Benefits &amp;amp; Challenges.”  This year’s panel will be moderated by Daniel Worledge, Distinguished Research Scientist, IBM Research. Panelists include:&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;• Kevin Conley, CEO, Applied Brain Research&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;• Masanori Hosomi, Principal Engineer, Sony Semiconductor Solutions&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;• Reza Kazerounian, Co-founder &amp;amp; President, Alif Semiconductor&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;• Tomoya Saito, Senior Principal Process Engineer, Renesas Electronics&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;• Max Simmons, CEO, Numem&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Registration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;  
Attendance at the 2025 MRAM Global Innovation Forum is complimentary but limited to 250 participants. &lt;a title=&quot;This external link will open in a new window&quot; href=&quot;https://us.cisionone.cision.com/c/eJwszkGO6yAQBNDTwI7ItAHDgkU2vkYETeOgb8IfIJnrjzya7SupqpIHi2oxnLzcjJbKOOv40wfYpNkSGmUjooQcgLRNawYVYnKZF2_cahapKUO08SElpmyN05GYWkZJ9K98iRrKSX0IY3NWMW-4iWhf2t6ugJ_-Oef_wdY7g53BPsqkcTtaO066YasM9k-hbwZ77aHm1t8XdTrKmD3M0l68UipBdDopDBIl-V94_AFb79KZRRve_UjhU8b1jWrB9kpvnK2nctCY1xgfsxPVq0MbmQAXFGBICoXKiai2RawBSQdcM2DgHw8_AQAA___FYGUe&quot;&gt;Registration&lt;/a&gt; is open until December 1, 2025. Lunch is included with registration.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/the-2025-mram-global-innovation-forum-to-showcase-mram-technology-innovations-advances-research-from-industry-experts/&quot;&gt;The 2025 MRAM Global Innovation Forum to Showcase MRAM Technology Innovations, Advances, &amp;amp; Research from Industry Experts&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com&quot;&gt;Semiconductor Digest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/the-2025-mram-global-innovation-forum-to-showcase-mram-technology-innovations-advances-research-from-industry-experts/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=the-2025-mram-global-innovation-forum-to-showcase-mram-technology-innovations-advances-research-from-industry-experts</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 22:38:22 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Navitas, Cyient Semiconductors Enter Into a Strategic Partnership</title>
      <link>https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/navitas-cyient-semiconductors-enter-into-a-strategic-partnership/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=navitas-cyient-semiconductors-enter-into-a-strategic-partnership</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/60ca50fa046b5dfa00dcdbe4afe8721fedbe411069563961be1471aa20e65faf?s=164&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&quot; alt=&quot;60ca50fa046b5dfa00dcdbe4afe8721fedbe4110&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;This external link will open in a new window&quot; href=&quot;http://email.prnewswire.com/ls/click?upn=u001.8CiUkFrLGqa7ynIpBWoM0v7EmeVPMGXDVN-2B7-2BRaQiLq7kUvVaLkXbTmmxlqtrncT7-2Fneq3FZYwTCAa7v0xdNlaqAx8ktJmqNdDcEY7eDWV4tVlwNEdvRwVIteCx33YPURzUaQ985oiKmnKV-2FBxefxfKFFdBngxiYKkFSFbWhqRjmmW0lH0FAi7U34ZLpOMVl6Ouz_KYGXew72n-2F6pWj7-2BRasUycgXIYa0Tsaf-2FC0Mt3FD5K18ixtlzIUnYNezQWtAD8nmcug3jU1qntGllDo-2B6qsQWO70vpT4cXS-2FtWQBZHfjnLnjnUUyb-2Bem7cTJeNM1bu5lXWiR5eEWzu9JXndbrzksVP4ORM-2FzC1OvrPjc-2FOFF2iCsA2Q-2Bw3MH8I63mPPyX2C4rm7YJ4wchxUk6I-2FXDtzp0avWoIaFYKLUCcfXntQkiFcZOjDTufB4Z20oAjiLw2ovjM9s4g6ZCHUxDB29z4oYTXRwBj1LqOexnKE1T5FVgauA-2BBOvay-2FUJiUTXJ09sVWWofYdUiWvp-2F2yWkz-2BY4qujuQVGEDgQlrhDOVf8mbX1GQCPDdm0fyKaEIEjya-2F5jZ6&quot;&gt;Navitas Semiconductor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a title=&quot;This external link will open in a new window&quot; href=&quot;http://email.prnewswire.com/ls/click?upn=u001.8CiUkFrLGqa7ynIpBWoM0v7EmeVPMGXDVN-2B7-2BRaQiLq7kUvVaLkXbTmmxlqtrncT7-2Fneq3FZYwTCAa7v0xdNlY9VzWsAr3-2FWnKLrJCdaPilO4Q6cfKYoH53NSex98p-2Bc9CHrUJQHR-2BWWmRdFhIQXX7aLGE0BpmZXYli73owMLeuR8J-2Ba4Vhaz6oQW-2BAYcA-2BrqzvG_KYGXew72n-2F6pWj7-2BRasUycgXIYa0Tsaf-2FC0Mt3FD5K18ixtlzIUnYNezQWtAD8nmcug3jU1qntGllDo-2B6qsQWO70vpT4cXS-2FtWQBZHfjnLnjnUUyb-2Bem7cTJeNM1bu5lXWiR5eEWzu9JXndbrzksVP4ORM-2FzC1OvrPjc-2FOFF2iCsA2Q-2Bw3MH8I63mPPyX2C4rm7YJ4wchxUk6I-2FXDtzp0avWoIaFYKLUCcfXntQkiFeG694deujifZVb4qVcajZZSt1UluLYcA5kfkXeAzch0NtBj9e-2BG-2FGhx0epGMv2Af5XkoGshaahvYG0VzUuY9x77JY6kBWJLseYXBZkPVu92Hc2fncJJlNeJpIuRHIp3lBGrxL8JM6-2FPSlpIqKPFjTN&quot;&gt;Cyient Semiconductors&lt;/a&gt; Private Limited have announced a strategic long-term partnership intended to advance the adoption of GaN technology in India and establish a complete, end-to-end GaN ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;Through this partnership, Navitas Semiconductor and Cyient Semiconductors intend to co-develop GaN products, digital and mixed signal ICs, GaN based system modules and design enablement platforms targeting India’s high voltage, high power market segments such as AI data centers, electric mobility, performance computing, energy grid infrastructure and industrial electrification.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The partnership seeks to build a robust local supply chain and manufacturing ecosystem in support of the Indian Government’s “Make in India” initiative. In addition, through this partnership Navitas and Cyient Semiconductor aims to deploy IC technology in accelerating solution development for high voltage and high-power markets.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;This is expected to include products based on Navitas’ existing GaN technologies, along with new products tailored for India’s unique market needs. Cyient Semiconductors’ work in establishing a secure local supply chain and ecosystem for GaN products in India will further accelerate time to market for developers and OEMs across the region.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Suman Narayan, CEO, Cyient Semiconductors, said,&lt;/b&gt; “This partnership represents a pivotal step in India’s semiconductor future in solving the complexities of power delivery at high voltages. By combining Navitas’ proven GaN technology with Cyient Semi’s design, manufacturing, and supply-chain strengths, we’re creating a self-sustaining ecosystem that will accelerate the market adoption of GaN. Our goal is to make GaN accessible to every OEM looking to design, build, and scale from India.”&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;“I believe the growth of GaN technology in India will exceed global trends, and Cyient Semiconductors is the perfect partner for Navitas to drive this revolution,” &lt;b&gt;said Chris Allexandre, President and CEO of Navitas&lt;/b&gt;. “Together, Navitas and Cyient will power India’s vision of India for India – innovation, by India, for the world.”&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;This initiative is intended to empower Indian design houses and OEMs with locally sourced GaN components and manufacturing support, enabling faster development cycles and reducing barriers to GaN adoption in India. It also reinforces Cyient Semiconductors’ ambition to driving semiconductor innovation, localization, and scalability across critical technology sectors.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;This collaboration between Cyient Semiconductors and Navitas establishes a direct channel for Indian customers to access GaN technology, along with reliable procurement, engineering collaboration and technical support.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/navitas-cyient-semiconductors-enter-into-a-strategic-partnership/&quot;&gt;Navitas, Cyient Semiconductors Enter Into a Strategic Partnership&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com&quot;&gt;Semiconductor Digest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/navitas-cyient-semiconductors-enter-into-a-strategic-partnership/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=navitas-cyient-semiconductors-enter-into-a-strategic-partnership</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 22:38:22 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>