<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Professional News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Curated articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 19:52:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>

    <item>
      <title>Verification and Reliability Methods For RRAM-Based Computing-in-Memory (Univ. of Bremen et al)</title>
      <link>https://semiengineering.com/verification-and-reliability-methods-for-rram-based-computing-in-memory-univ-of-bremen-et-al/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://semiengineering.com/wp-content/uploads/AdobeStock_839148332-06-19-24-scaled.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;AdobeStock_839148332-06-19-24-scaled.jpe&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new technical paper titled “Special Session Paper: Formal Verification Techniques and Reliability Methods for RRAM-based Computing-in-Memory” was published by researchers at University of Bremen, DFKI GmbH, University of Florida and TU Munich.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;“Computing-in-memory (CIM) has gained immense traction owing to the benefits it provides in power, performance, and area. CIM can be done on a large variety of memory elements like SRAM, DRAM, RRAM, etc. In this work, we focus on the techniques using RRAM for the computations. First, we explain the stateful and non-stateful techniques to perform Logic-in-Memory (LiM) operations using RRAM crossbars. We discuss the methods that are used to guarantee the correctness of the mapping/micro-operations obtained from mapping tools like SIMPLE-MAGIC. Second, we discuss the flow-based computing techniques that alleviate the write operations when performing the LiM operations and use the sneak-path currents to perform the computations. We discuss the formal verification strategies developed to guarantee the correctness of the logic operations using flow-based computing. Lastly, we discuss the techniques that have been developed to enable reliable computations using RRAM devices even in the presence of variations, such as error suppression and error reduction techniques. Finally, we explain a technique employing basis vectors to reduce the necessity to reprogram RRAM-based crossbars.”&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;Find the &lt;a href=&quot;https://agra.informatik.uni-bremen.de/doc/konf/DFT2025_CKJ.pdf&quot;&gt;technical paper here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;Jha, Chandan Kumar, Sumit Kumar Jha, Ulf Schlichtmann, and Rolf Drechsler. “Special Session Paper: Formal Verification Techniques and Reliability Methods for RRAM-based Computing-in-Memory.”&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://semiengineering.com/verification-and-reliability-methods-for-rram-based-computing-in-memory-univ-of-bremen-et-al/&quot;&gt;Verification and Reliability Methods For RRAM-Based Computing-in-Memory (Univ. of Bremen et al)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://semiengineering.com&quot;&gt;Semiconductor Engineering&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:40:49 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Exynos 2600 Has Yet To Enter Mass Production, With Latest Report Downplaying Previous Updates Regarding Samsung’s First 2nm GAA Chipset’s Progress</title>
      <link>https://wccftech.com/exynos-2600-yet-to-enter-mass-production-despite-samsung-announcing-it/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/exynos-2600-yet-to-enter-mass-production-despite-samsung-announcing-it/&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;410&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Exynos-2600-5-728x410.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A new report claims that the Exynos 2600 has yet to enter mass production&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Samsung was previously reported to have a headstart in mass producing its first 2nm GAA chipset, the Exynos 2600, back in late September, where the company’s yields were estimated at 50 percent. Given that the Korean giant recently unveiled its upcoming SoC by showcasing its first trailer, it was immediately assumed that the full-scale manufacturing was already underway. Unfortunately, that doesn’t appear to be the case, with an update mentioning that the Exynos 2600 is expected to enter the production block soon. Samsung could be experimenting with higher yields to reduce defective Exynos 2600 units, as DRAM and NAND flash […]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read full article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/exynos-2600-yet-to-enter-mass-production-despite-samsung-announcing-it/&quot;&gt;https://wccftech.com/exynos-2600-yet-to-enter-mass-production-despite-samsung-announcing-it/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:37:47 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Apple iPhone Fold Tipped To Launch As An eSIM-Only Foldable Smartphone</title>
      <link>https://wccftech.com/apple-iphone-fold-tipped-to-launch-as-an-esim-only-foldable-smartphone/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/apple-iphone-fold-tipped-to-launch-as-an-esim-only-foldable-smartphone/&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;410&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Apple-iPhone-Fold-728x410.webp&quot; alt=&quot;A concept image of a foldable Apple iPhone showing the home screen with app icons like Photos, Camera, and Safari, set on a wooden surface with a 9:41 time display.&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apple is apparently trying to save as much internal space as possible for the iPhone Fold&apos;s heftier components by eliminating all non-essential elements, such as a dedicated SIM card tray, and opting for an eSIM-only design instead. The Chinese tipster Instant Digital echoes previous comments by Mark Gurman and Ming-Chi Kuo in predicting an eSIM-only design for the Apple iPhone Fold The Chinese tipster, Instant Digital, has now postulated that Apple is likely to launch the iPhone Fold next year as an eSIM-only foldable smartphone. In doing so, the tipster has echoed the previous comments by Bloomberg&apos;s Mark Gurman and […]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read full article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/apple-iphone-fold-tipped-to-launch-as-an-esim-only-foldable-smartphone/&quot;&gt;https://wccftech.com/apple-iphone-fold-tipped-to-launch-as-an-esim-only-foldable-smartphone/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:37:47 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Dutch minister admits he was blindsided by China in Nexperia chip crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/article/3335416/dutch-minister-admits-being-blindsided-chinas-retaliation-nexperia-chip-crisis?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_image_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/06/ba61fa0b-546f-4b36-a9e4-7785d456fc0c_f199e6e2.jpg?itok=zBiy7h4Y&amp;amp;v=1764951732&quot; alt=&quot;ba61fa0b-546f-4b36-a9e4-7785d456fc0c_f19&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Export controls may have been the economic weapon of choice in 2025, but the Dutch minister at the centre of the Nexperia crisis has admitted he was blindsided by Beijing when it blocked the company’s chips from leaving China.  
His concession raises fresh questions over how much planning went into the decision to reach for a Cold War-era law to intervene in the Chinese-owned, Dutch-headquartered chipmaker in September, a move that triggered a supply chain shock in the global automotive...</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:28:41 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Ceva-XC21 Named &quot;Best IP/Processor of the Year&quot; at EE Awards Asia</title>
      <link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/cevaxc21-named-best-ipprocessor-of-the-year-at-ee-awards-asia-302634148.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ceva-XC21™ Recognized for advancing cellular IoT and 5G connectivity with ultra-efficient, AI-enabled DSP architecture for cost-sensitive IoT and smart-home devices&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;ROCKVILLE, Md.&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Dec. 5, 2025&lt;/span&gt; /PRNewswire/ -- Ceva, Inc. (NASDAQ: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/#financial-modal&quot;&gt;CEVA&lt;/a&gt;), the leading licensor of silicon and software IP for the Smart Edge, today announced that its Ceva–XC21™ IoT communication DSP has been awarded Best IP/Processor of the Year at the prestigious EE Awards Asia ceremony in Taipei. The EE Awards Asia recognize standout products and companies across the region&apos;s electronics industry, with finalists selected by a global editorial panel and winners chosen by the EE Times and EDN reader communities in Taiwan and Asia.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cellular IoT on the Rise&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;The cellular IoT market is entering a period of rapid expansion, driven by the migration from LTE to 5G technologies. According to Omdia, 5G Reduced Capability (RedCap) and enhanced RedCap (eRedCap) connections are forecast to reach nearly 1 billion by 2030. LPWA standards like NB-IoT, LTE-M, LoRaWAN, and Sub-1GHz will also dominate massive IoT deployments. The Ceva-XC21 DSP is purpose-built to address this growth, delivering ultra-efficient, AI-enabled processing for cellular IoT and 5G/5G-Advanced devices.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Michael Boukaya, Chief Operating Officer of Ceva, commented: &quot;Winning Best IP/Processor of the Year for Ceva-XC21 underscores our commitment to driving innovation in wireless connectivity. By combining ultra–efficient DSP processing with embedded AI, The Ceva-XC21 enables smarter connectivity for billions of devices - from IoT sensors to advanced smart–home gateways. This award affirms our vision to deliver the IP that makes ubiquitous connectivity practical and scalable for the next decade of connected innovation.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Why Ceva-XC21 won: measurable efficiency with AI&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;–ready scalability&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;Purpose–built for low–power, cost– and size–optimized cellular IoT modems and 5G/5G–Advanced devices, Ceva–XC21 is a scalable, dual–thread IoT processor with built–in AI/ML support to apply machine learning to modem algorithms and network efficiency. Available in multiple configurations - including single– or dual–thread options and 32 or 64 MAC units, the Ceva-XC21 lets designers tune power, performance, and area for everything from compact IoT sensors and smartwatches to advanced smart–home gateways and IoT hubs relying on robust cellular backhaul, including 5G Fixed Wireless Access (FWA).&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;ul type=&quot;disc&quot;&gt; &lt;li&gt;Optimized for RedCap/eRedCap &amp;amp; LTE Cat–M/Cat–1: Reliable cellular backhaul for smart–home hubs, gateways, smartwatches and IoT devices in cost–sensitive, size–constrained designs.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;AI inside the modem path: Built–in AI/ML improves link robustness, latency, and energy efficiency—key for Physical AI deployments at the edge.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Scalable architecture: Configurable from 32 to 64 MAC units, single or dual thread, to balance power, performance, and area across diverse device classes.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Future–ready: Designed for 5G–Advanced and pre–6G workloads, including NTN and VSAT terminals, ensuring long–term viability.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Proven gains: Up to 1.8× performance vs. prior generation and 48% area reduction in top configurations.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Availability&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;Ceva-XC21 DSP is available for licensing today. For more information, visit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573600-1&amp;amp;h=527311822&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ceva-ip.com%2Fproduct%2Fceva-xc21%2F&amp;amp;a=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ceva-ip.com%2Fproduct%2Fceva-xc21%2F&quot;&gt;https://www.ceva-ip.com/product/ceva-xc21/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About EE Awards Asia&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;The EE Awards Asia celebrate the best products, companies, and individuals across the continent&apos;s electronics industry. Judging and selection are undertaken by a global panel of experts, followed by voting from EE Times and EDN reader communities in Taiwan and Asia.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Ceva, Inc.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;At Ceva, we are passionate about bringing new levels of innovation to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573600-1&amp;amp;h=683728245&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ceva-ip.com%2F%3Futm_source%3DPR%26utm_medium%3DPRNewswire&amp;amp;a=smart+edge&quot;&gt;smart edge&lt;/a&gt;. Our &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573600-1&amp;amp;h=3761368357&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ceva-ip.com%2Fsolutions%2Fwireless-connectivity%2F%3Futm_source%3DPR%26utm_medium%3DPRNewswire&amp;amp;a=wireless+communications&quot;&gt;wireless communications&lt;/a&gt;, sensing and &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573600-1&amp;amp;h=1557605033&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ceva-ip.com%2Fsolutions%2Fedge-ai%2F%3Futm_source%3DPR%26utm_medium%3DPRNewswire&amp;amp;a=Edge+AI&quot;&gt;Edge AI&lt;/a&gt; technologies are at the heart of some of today&apos;s most advanced smart edge products. From &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573600-1&amp;amp;h=1188240548&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ceva-ip.com%2Fproduct%2Frivierawaves-bluetooth-platforms%2F%3Futm_source%3DPR%26utm_medium%3DPRNewswire&amp;amp;a=Bluetooth&quot;&gt;Bluetooth&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573600-1&amp;amp;h=1520261233&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ceva-ip.com%2Fproduct%2Frivierawaves-wi-fi-platforms%2F%3Futm_source%3DPR%26utm_medium%3DPRNewswire&amp;amp;a=Wi-Fi&quot;&gt;Wi-Fi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573600-1&amp;amp;h=1690959462&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ceva-ip.com%2Fproduct%2Frivierawaves-uwb-platform%2F%3Futm_source%3DPR%26utm_medium%3DPRNewswire&amp;amp;a=UWB&quot;&gt;UWB&lt;/a&gt; and 5G platform IP for ubiquitous, robust communications, to scalable Edge AI &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573600-1&amp;amp;h=3410323359&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ceva-ip.com%2Fproduct%2Fceva-neupro-m%2F%3Futm_source%3DPR%26utm_medium%3DPRNewswire&amp;amp;a=NPU+IP&quot;&gt;NPU IP&lt;/a&gt;s, &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573600-1&amp;amp;h=482037125&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ceva-ip.com%2Fproduct%2Fceva-motionengine-chips%2F%3Futm_source%3DPR%26utm_medium%3DPRNewswire&amp;amp;a=sensor+fusion&quot;&gt;sensor fusion&lt;/a&gt; processors and embedded application software that make devices smarter, we have the broadest portfolio of IP to connect, sense and infer data more reliably and efficiently. We deliver differentiated solutions that combine outstanding performance at ultra-low power within a very small silicon footprint. Our goal is simple – to deliver the silicon and software IP to enable a smarter, safer, and more interconnected world. This philosophy is in practice today, with Ceva powering more than 20 billion of the world&apos;s most innovative smart edge products from AI-infused smartwatches, IoT devices and wearables to autonomous vehicles and 5G mobile networks.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Our headquarters are in Rockville, Maryland with a global customer base supported by operations worldwide. Our employees are among the leading experts in their areas of specialty, consistently solving the most complex design challenges, enabling our customers to bring innovative smart edge products to market.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Ceva: Powering the Smart Edge™&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Visit us at &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573600-1&amp;amp;h=795650782&amp;amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.ceva-ip.com%2F&amp;amp;a=www.ceva-ip.com&quot;&gt;www.ceva-ip.com&lt;/a&gt; and follow us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573600-1&amp;amp;h=1209988728&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.linkedin.com%2Fcompany%2Fceva&amp;amp;a=LinkedIn&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573600-1&amp;amp;h=2414575621&amp;amp;u=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.twitter.com%2FCEVA_IP&amp;amp;a=X&quot;&gt;X&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573600-1&amp;amp;h=304362356&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fcevadsp&amp;amp;a=YouTube&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573600-1&amp;amp;h=3829824311&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.facebook.com%2FCEVAIP&amp;amp;a=Facebook%2C&quot;&gt;Facebook,&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4573600-1&amp;amp;h=2353938516&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.instagram.com%2Fceva_ip%2F&amp;amp;a=Instagram&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;SOURCE Ceva, Inc.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://rt.prnewswire.com/rt.gif?NewsItemId=SF40334&amp;amp;Transmission_Id=202512051045PR_NEWS_USPR_____SF40334&amp;amp;DateId=20251205&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:05:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>The New York Times is suing Perplexity for copyright infringement</title>
      <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/12/05/the-new-york-times-is-suing-perplexity-for-copyright-infringement/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/07/GettyImages-2150495091.jpg?resize=1200,825&quot; alt=&quot;GettyImages-2150495091.jpg?resize=1200,8&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;The New York Times filed a copyright lawsuit against Perplexity, joining other publishers using legal action as leverage to force AI companies into licensing deals that compensate content creators.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:05:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Intel admits it needs more Core Ultra 200-series wafers — &apos;If we had more Lunar Lake wafers, we would be selling more Lunar Lake&apos;</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/cpus/intel-admits-it-needs-more-core-ultra-200-series-wafers-if-we-had-more-lunar-lake-wafers-we-would-be-selling-more-lunar-lake</link>
      <description>Intel needs more Core Ultra 200-series &apos;Arrow Lake&apos; and &apos;Lunar Lake&apos; wafers from TSMC as demand exceeds supply.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 16:00:03 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>The New York Times sues Perplexity for producing ‘verbatim’ copies of its work</title>
      <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/839006/new-york-times-perplexity-lawsuit-copyright</link>
      <description> 
 
&lt;img alt=&quot;A photo showing the New York Times building&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/12/gettyimages-2249036304.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;crop=0,0,100,100&quot;&gt; 
	 
		 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2025/12/05/technology/new-york-times-perplexity-ai-lawsuit.html&quot;&gt;has escalated its legal battle against the AI startup Perplexity&lt;/a&gt;, as it’s now suing the AI “answer engine” for allegedly producing and profiting from responses that are “verbatim or substantially similar copies” of the publication’s work.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
&lt;p&gt;The lawsuit, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.documentcloud.org/documents/26341080-nyt-perplexity-filing-dec-2025/&quot;&gt;filed in a New York federal court on Friday&lt;/a&gt;, claims Perplexity “unlawfully crawls, scrapes, copies, and distributes” content from the &lt;em&gt;NYT&lt;/em&gt;. It comes after the outlet’s repeated demands for Perplexity to stop using content from its website, as the &lt;em&gt;NYT&lt;/em&gt; sent cease-and-desist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/15/24270774/new-york-times-cease-and-desist-letter-perplexity-ai-search-engine&quot;&gt;notices to the AI startup last year&lt;/a&gt; and most recently in July, according to the lawsuit.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/2025/12/04/chicago-tribune-sues-perplexity/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Chicago Tribune&lt;/em&gt; also filed a copyright lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; against Perplexity on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt; sued OpenAI for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2023/12/27/24016212/new-york-times-openai-microsoft-lawsuit-copyright-infringement&quot;&gt;copyright infringement in December 2023&lt;/a&gt;, and later &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/676291/new-york-times-ai-deal-amazon&quot;&gt;inked a deal with Amazon&lt;/a&gt;, bringing its content to products like Alexa.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
&lt;p&gt;Perplexity &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2024/10/21/24275924/news-corp-wall-street-journal-perplexity-lawsuit-copyright-infringement&quot;&gt;became the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/777344/perplexity-lawsuit-encyclopedia-britannica-merriam-webster&quot;&gt;subject of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/804660/reddit-suing-perplexity-data-scrapers-ai-lawsuit&quot;&gt;several&lt;/a&gt; lawsuits &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2024/6/27/24187405/perplexity-ai-twitter-lie-plagiarism&quot;&gt;after reporting from &lt;em&gt;Forbes&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Wired &lt;/em&gt;revealed that the&lt;/a&gt; startup had been skirting websites’ paywalls to provide AI-generated summaries — and in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/perplexity-plagiarized-our-story-about-how-perplexity-is-a-bullshit-machine/&quot;&gt;some cases, copies&lt;/a&gt; — of their work. The&lt;em&gt; NYT&lt;/em&gt; makes similar accusations in its lawsuit, stating that Perplexity’s crawlers “have intentionally ignored or evaded technical content protection measures,” such &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/24067997/robots-txt-ai-text-file-web-crawlers-spiders&quot;&gt;as the robots.txt file&lt;/a&gt;, which indicates the parts of a website crawlers can access.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
&lt;p&gt;Perplexity attempted to smooth things over by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2024/7/30/24208979/perplexity-publishers-program-ad-revenue-sharing-ai-time-fortune-der-spiegel&quot;&gt;launching a program to share ad revenue with publishers last year&lt;/a&gt;, which it later expanded to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/ai-artificial-intelligence/765078/perplexity-expanded-its-revenue-sharing-program-with-publishers&quot;&gt;include its Comet web browser in August&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
&lt;p&gt;“By copying The Times’s copyrighted content and creating substitutive output derived from its works, obviating the need for users to visit The Times’s website or purchase its newspaper, Perplexity is misappropriating substantial subscription, advertising, licensing, and affiliate revenue opportunities that belong rightfully and exclusively to The Times,” the lawsuit states. &lt;/p&gt; 
 
&lt;p&gt;The&lt;em&gt; NYT&lt;/em&gt; is seeking damages and is also asking the court to permanently block the AI startup from engaging in its allegedly unlawful behavior. “Publishers have been suing new tech companies for a hundred years, starting with radio, TV, the internet, social media and now AI,” Perplexity spokesperson Jesse Dwyer said in an emailed statement to &lt;em&gt;The Verge&lt;/em&gt;. “Fortunately it’s never worked, or we’d all be talking about this by telegraph.”&lt;/p&gt; 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update, December 5th: &lt;/strong&gt;Added a statement from Perplexity.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:52:39 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>SoftBank CEO Masayoshi Son wants to build ‘Trump Industrial Parks’ across the nation, report claims — project proposes using federal land to build manufacturing sites for data center infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/softbank-ceo-masayoshi-son-wants-to-build-trump-industrial-parks-across-the-nation-report-claims-project-proposes-using-federal-land-to-build-manufacturing-sites-for-data-center-infrastructure</link>
      <description>SoftBank proposes building multiple industrial parks across the U.S. on federal land to manufacture semiconductors and other AI infrastructure.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:50:20 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>An Iron-On Electronic Circuit to Create Wearable Tech</title>
      <link>https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/an-iron-on-electronic-circuit-to-create-wearable-tech/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=an-iron-on-electronic-circuit-to-create-wearable-tech</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/60ca50fa046b5dfa00dcdbe4afe8721fedbe411069563961be1471aa20e65faf?s=164&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&quot; alt=&quot;60ca50fa046b5dfa00dcdbe4afe8721fedbe4110&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Iron-on patches can repair clothing or add personal flair to backpacks and hats. And now they could power wearable tech, too. Researchers reporting in &lt;em&gt;ACS Applied Materials &amp;amp; Interfaces&lt;/em&gt; have combined liquid metal and a heat-activated adhesive to create an electrically conductive patch that bonds to fabric when heated with a hot iron. In demonstrations, circuits ironed onto a square of fabric lit up LEDs and attached an iron-on microphone to a button-up shirt.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;“E-textiles and wearable electronics can enable diverse applications from health care and environmental monitoring to robotics and human-machine interfaces. Our work advances this exciting area by creating iron-on soft electronics that can be rapidly and robustly integrated into a wide range of fabrics,” says Michael D. Bartlett, a researcher at Virginia Tech and corresponding author on the study.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The flexible, soft nature of fabric makes it difficult to integrate electric circuitry into smart clothing and wearable technology. For example, printed-on conductive ink circuits can be damaged when exposed to the elements, and sandwiching the liquid metal circuits between polymer sheets provides protection but not stretchability. So, Bartlett and colleagues wanted to try a different approach, combining liquid metals and rubber to produce a stretchable film that can be ironed onto fabric and conduct electricity.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;Bartlett and the team added microscopic droplets of a gallium-indium alloy into a polyurethane mixture and poured the composite into a thin layer. After air-drying for a day, it formed a soft, electrically conductive elastic sheet. Then they ironed small rectangular pieces of the sheets onto various fabrics (plain weave polyester, cotton twill, knit spandex and mesh jersey). The polymer in the conductive patches created strong bonds with the fibers, keeping the layers together once they cooled.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate the iron-on circuit’s potential applications, the researchers created two proofs of concept:&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;ul&gt;  
&lt;li&gt;Their university’s logo, ironed onto a piece of fabric, with five LEDs. The flexible circuit kept the LEDs lit when repeatedly folded, twisted and stretched.&lt;/li&gt;  
&lt;li&gt;A stretchable wire microphone inside a shirt, with the ironed-on circuit relaying power and audio signal underneath the garment and out to an external recording device. The ironed-on microphone recorded sound across the full human hearing range with performance comparable to a traditional microphone setup, and with less noticeable bulk.&lt;/li&gt;  
&lt;/ul&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;This conductive patch technology isn’t just for attaching rigid components such as LEDs, however. The researchers say it could also be integrated into soft circuits, soft robots and other wearable electronic devices.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/an-iron-on-electronic-circuit-to-create-wearable-tech/&quot;&gt;An Iron-On Electronic Circuit to Create Wearable Tech&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com&quot;&gt;Semiconductor Digest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:49:17 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>The New York Times and Chicago Tribune sue Perplexity over alleged copyright infringement</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/ai/the-new-york-times-and-chicago-tribune-sue-perplexity-over-alleged-copyright-infringement-153656431.html?src=rss</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Chicago Tribune&lt;/em&gt; have filed separate lawsuits against Perplexity over alleged copyright infringement. The &lt;em&gt;Times &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://shopping.yahoo.com/rdlw?merchantId=c813ae39-7d58-41cb-ac66-ad830606ceef&amp;amp;siteId=us-engadget&amp;amp;pageId=1p-autolink&amp;amp;contentUuid=6fdd646f-f2ac-40dc-86d7-a25e96690acb&amp;amp;featureId=text-link&amp;amp;merchantName=The+New+York+Times&amp;amp;linkText=said&amp;amp;custData=eyJzb3VyY2VOYW1lIjoiV2ViLURlc2t0b3AtVmVyaXpvbiIsImxhbmRpbmdVcmwiOiJodHRwczovL3d3dy5ueXRpbWVzLmNvbS8yMDI1LzEyLzA1L3RlY2hub2xvZ3kvbmV3LXlvcmstdGltZXMtcGVycGxleGl0eS1haS1sYXdzdWl0Lmh0bWwiLCJjb250ZW50VXVpZCI6IjZmZGQ2NDZmLWYyYWMtNDBkYy04NmQ3LWEyNWU5NjY5MGFjYiIsIm9yaWdpbmFsVXJsIjoiaHR0cHM6Ly93d3cubnl0aW1lcy5jb20vMjAyNS8xMi8wNS90ZWNobm9sb2d5L25ldy15b3JrLXRpbWVzLXBlcnBsZXhpdHktYWktbGF3c3VpdC5odG1sIn0&amp;amp;signature=AQAAAfSuVsew9F-otmqDn9dUt7Shz53Z1aliibkYMqUlF2iy&amp;amp;gcReferrer=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nytimes.com%2F2025%2F12%2F05%2Ftechnology%2Fnew-york-times-perplexity-ai-lawsuit.html&quot;&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; it had sent Perplexity several cease-and-desist demands to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/ai/the-new-york-times-tells-perplexity-to-stop-using-its-content-175853131.html&quot;&gt;stop using its content&lt;/a&gt; until the two reached an agreement, but the AI company persisted in doing so. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the lawsuit [&lt;a href=&quot;https://nytco-assets.nytimes.com/2025/12/NYT-Perplexity-Filing-Dec-2025.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;], the &lt;em&gt;Times &lt;/em&gt;accused Perplexity of infringing on its copyrights at two main stages. First, by scraping its website (including in real time) to train AI models and feed content into the likes of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/ai/claude-can-now-compartmentalize-as-part-of-a-major-memory-upgrade-170000194.html&quot;&gt;Claude chatbot&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/ai/perplexitys-comet-ai-browser-is-now-free-for-everyone-170017509.html&quot;&gt;Comet browser&lt;/a&gt;. Second, in the output of Perplexity&apos;s products, with the &lt;em&gt;Times &lt;/em&gt;accusing the company’s generative AI products of often reproducing its articles verbatim. The &lt;em&gt;Times &lt;/em&gt;also says Perplexity damaged its brand by falsely attributing completely fabricated information (aka hallucinations) to the newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Chicago Tribune&lt;/em&gt; also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chicagotribune.com/2025/12/04/chicago-tribune-perplexity-ai-copyright-infringement/&quot;&gt;filed a lawsuit&lt;/a&gt; against Perplexity for similar reasons. &quot;Perplexity’s genAI products generate outputs that are identical or substantially similar to the Chicago Tribune’s content,” the newspaper claimed in its suit. “Upon information and belief, Perplexity has unlawfully copied millions of copyrighted &lt;em&gt;Chicago Tribune&lt;/em&gt; stories, videos, images and other works to power its products and tools.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These lawsuits are the latest in dozens of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/social-media/reddit-sues-perplexity-and-three-other-companies-for-allegedly-using-its-content-without-paying-205136436.html&quot;&gt;legal cases&lt;/a&gt; involving &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/ai/perplexity-signs-deal-to-use-getty-images-152343900.html&quot;&gt;copyright holders&lt;/a&gt; and AI companies in the US. The &lt;em&gt;Times, &lt;/em&gt;for instance, previously &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/the-new-york-times-is-suing-openai-and-microsoft-for-copyright-infringement-181212615.html&quot;&gt;sued&lt;/a&gt; OpenAI and Microsoft. It accused the companies of training their large language models on millions of its articles without permission. That case is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/ai/openai-no-longer-has-to-preserve-all-of-its-chatgpt-data-with-some-exceptions-192422093.html&quot;&gt;ongoing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Copyright holders have licensed their content to AI companies in some cases, though. OpenAI has struck multiple deals with media companies. The &lt;em&gt;Times &lt;/em&gt;and Amazon &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/amazon-and-the-new-york-times-enter-ai-related-licensing-agreement-155019578.html&quot;&gt;reached an agreement&lt;/a&gt; this year that&apos;s said to be worth as much as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/ai/the-new-york-times-and-amazons-ai-licensing-deal-is-reportedly-worth-up-to-25-million-per-year-135523853.html&quot;&gt;$25 million per year&lt;/a&gt; to the media company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/ai/the-new-york-times-and-chicago-tribune-sue-perplexity-over-alleged-copyright-infringement-153656431.html?src=rss</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:40:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>SoftBank in Talks to Buy Data-Center Investor DigitalBridge</title>
      <link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-05/softbank-said-in-talks-to-buy-data-center-investor-digitalbridge</link>
      <description>SoftBank Group Corp. is in talks to acquire DigitalBridge Group Inc., a private equity firm that invests in assets such as data centers, as it seeks to take advantage of an AI-driven boom in digital infrastructure, according to people with knowledge of the matter.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:19:38 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Harnessing human-AI collaboration for an AI roadmap that moves beyond pilots</title>
      <link>https://www.technologyreview.com/2025/12/05/1128730/harnessing-human-ai-collaboration-for-an-ai-roadmap-that-moves-beyond-pilots/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past year has marked a turning point in the corporate AI conversation. After a period of eager experimentation, organizations are now confronting a more complex reality: While investment in AI has never been higher, the path from pilot to production remains elusive. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.concentrix.com/insights/research/turning-ai-ambition-into-enterprise-scale-impact/&quot;&gt;Three-quarters&lt;/a&gt; of enterprises remain stuck in experimentation mode, despite mounting pressure to convert early tests into operational gains.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.concentrix.com/insights/webinars/why-agentic-ai-roadmap-decides-who-wins-2026/?utm_source=mit&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=000955-gl-ut-en-us-agentic-ai-framework&amp;amp;utm_campaign=agentic-ai-mit-webinar&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;1920&quot; height=&quot;1080&quot; src=&quot;https://wp.technologyreview.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Concentrix-social-card-v2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;div&gt; 
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.concentrix.com/insights/webinars/why-agentic-ai-roadmap-decides-who-wins-2026/?utm_source=mit&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=000955-gl-ut-en-us-agentic-ai-framework&amp;amp;utm_campaign=agentic-ai-mit-webinar&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#007380;font-size:16px;&quot;&gt;WATCH THE WEBCAST&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;“Most organizations can suffer from what we like to call PTSD, or process technology skills and data challenges,” says Shirley Hung, partner at Everest Group. “They have rigid, fragmented workflows that don’t adapt well to change, technology systems that don’t speak to each other, talent that is really immersed in low-value tasks rather than creating high impact. And they are buried in endless streams of information, but no unified fabric to tie it all together.”&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;The central challenge, then, lies in rethinking how people, processes, and technology work together.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;Across industries as different as customer experience and agricultural equipment, the same pattern is emerging: Traditional organizational structures—centralized decision-making, fragmented workflows, data spread across incompatible systems—are proving too rigid to support agentic AI. To unlock value, leaders must rethink how decisions are made, how work is executed, and what humans should uniquely contribute.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;“It is very important that humans continue to verify the content. And that is where you’re going to see more energy being put into,” Ryan Peterson, EVP and chief product officer at Concentrix.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;Much of the conversation centered on what can be described as the next major unlock: operationalizing human-AI collaboration. Rather than positioning AI as a standalone tool or a “virtual worker,” this approach reframes AI as a system-level capability that augments human judgment, accelerates execution, and reimagines work from end to end. That shift requires organizations to map the value they want to create; design workflows that blend human oversight with AI-driven automation; and build the data, governance, and security foundations that make these systems trustworthy.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;“My advice would be to expect some delays because you need to make sure you secure the data,” says Heidi Hough, VP for North America aftermarket at Valmont. “As you think about commercializing or operationalizing any piece of using AI, if you start from ground zero and have governance at the forefront, I think that will help with outcomes.”&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;Early adopters are already showing what this looks like in practice: starting with low-risk operational use cases, shaping data into tightly scoped enclaves, embedding governance into everyday decision-making, and empowering business leaders, not just technologists, to identify where AI can create measurable impact. The result is a new blueprint for AI maturity grounded in reengineering how modern enterprises operate.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;“Optimization is really about doing existing things better, but reimagination is about discovering entirely new things that are worth doing,” says Hung.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.concentrix.com/insights/webinars/why-agentic-ai-roadmap-decides-who-wins-2026/?utm_source=mit&amp;amp;utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_content=000955-gl-ut-en-us-agentic-ai-framework&amp;amp;utm_campaign=agentic-ai-mit-webinar&quot;&gt;Watch the webcast.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This webcast is produced in partnership with Concentrix.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This content was produced by Insights, the custom content arm of MIT Technology Review. It was not written by MIT Technology Review’s editorial staff. It was researched, designed, and written by human writers, editors, analysts, and illustrators. This includes the writing of surveys and collection of data for surveys. AI tools that may have been used were limited to secondary production processes that passed thorough human review.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:18:51 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>NGK to Triple Production Capacity for Translucent Alumina Wafer</title>
      <link>https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/ngk-to-triple-production-capacity-for-translucent-alumina-wafer/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=ngk-to-triple-production-capacity-for-translucent-alumina-wafer</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/60ca50fa046b5dfa00dcdbe4afe8721fedbe411069563961be1471aa20e65faf?s=164&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&quot; alt=&quot;60ca50fa046b5dfa00dcdbe4afe8721fedbe4110&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NGK INSULATORS, LTD. will triple its production capacity for the Translucent Alumina Wafer by fiscal 2027 to meet growing demand for chiplet integration, a key technology in advanced fields such as AI and autonomous driving. Through this expansion, the NGK Group aims to establish a stable supply system and achieve net sales of 20 billion yen in the high-performance semiconductor market by fiscal 2030.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;With the rapid spread of generative AI, demand for high-performance semiconductors is increasing. The Translucent Alumina Wafer serves as a support wafer*1 used to temporarily hold semiconductor chips during chiplet integration*2, a technology that combines multiple small semiconductor chips to achieve high performance. As such, the Translucent Alumina Wafer is attracting attention as an essential component in the chiplet integration process of semiconductor manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The Translucent Alumina Wafer uses HICERAM*3, a translucent ceramic material that NGK has developed and refined over many years. In addition to its light-transmitting properties, this material offers high rigidity and durability, significantly reducing warping and breakage during manufacturing—issues commonly seen with conventional glass support wafers. This improvement enhances process stability for customers and contributes to reduced product loss and improved quality.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;As part of this capital investment, NGK will enhance the production facilities of its subsidiary NGK CERAMIC DEVICE CO., LTD. (Komaki City, Aichi Prefecture), which is responsible for manufacturing, while also introducing new forming and firing equipment at NGK ELECTRONICS DEVICES, INC.*4 (Mine City, Yamaguchi Prefecture), which handles the upstream processes. These enhancements will expand the Group’s overall production capacity to approximately three times the current level and establish a stable supply system.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;Under its medium- to long-term vision, “NGK Group Vision Road to 2050” looking ahead to 2050, the NGK Group is promoting a transformation of its business portfolio toward the Carbon Neutral (CN) and Digital Society (DS) fields. Toward 2030, a milestone, the Group is pursuing the New Value 1000 initiative, which aims to generate over 100.0 billion yen in net sales from new businesses. The Translucent Alumina Wafer, as a key component supporting the production of next-generation semiconductors, will contribute to the advancement of the digital society.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;Going forward, NGK will continue to leverage its proprietary ceramic technologies to help address social challenges in the Carbon Neutral and Digital Society fields.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/ngk-to-triple-production-capacity-for-translucent-alumina-wafer/&quot;&gt;NGK to Triple Production Capacity for Translucent Alumina Wafer&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com&quot;&gt;Semiconductor Digest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 15:38:57 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>