<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Recap News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:39:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    
    <!-- Real-time Hub Link -->
    <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
    
    <!-- Self Link (using GitHack for correct headers) -->
    <atom:link href="https://raw.githack.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS/main/Semiconductor-RSS.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <item>
      <title>To Beat China at Drug Innovation, Big Pharma and Generics Need the Supreme Court to End This Patent Absurdity</title>
      <link>https://ipwatchdog.com/2025/12/08/beat-china-drug-innovation-big-pharma-generics-need-supreme-court-end-patent-absurdity/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ipwatchdog.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/opinion11-21.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;opinion11-21.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What&apos;s really holding America back in the biopharma race against China isn&apos;t just Beijing&apos;s subsidies or cheaper labor. It&apos;s the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit&apos;s self-inflicted wound: a court so panel-dependent that no one—brand or generic—knows which rule will apply until the panel is drawn. The Supreme Court can fix this in one stroke by granting certiorari in MSN Pharmaceuticals v. Novartis (No. 25-225) and killing the bizarre &quot;after-arising technology&quot; exception that lets old, vague patents swallow future inventions.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipwatchdog.com/2025/12/08/beat-china-drug-innovation-big-pharma-generics-need-supreme-court-end-patent-absurdity/&quot;&gt;To Beat China at Drug Innovation, Big Pharma and Generics Need the Supreme Court to End This Patent Absurdity&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipwatchdog.com&quot;&gt;IPWatchdog.com | Patents &amp;amp; Intellectual Property Law&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">[object Object]</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:18:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Nvidia reportedly wins H200 exports to China — US Department of Commerce set to ease restrictions for full Hopper AI GPU</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/gpus/nvidia-reportedly-wins-h200-exports-to-china-us-department-of-commerce-set-to-ease-restrictions-for-full-hopper-ai-gpu</link>
      <description>The U.S. government is reportedly preparing to let Nvidia ship its H200 accelerators to China, a move that could restore Nvidia’s influence in the Chinese AI market and reinforce CUDA’s dominance, but the question is if Beijing agrees to accept this hardware.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">[object Object]</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:08:21 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Navitas and Cyient partner to accelerate GaN adoption in India</title>
      <link>https://www.semiconductor-today.com/news_items/2025/dec/navitas-081225.shtml</link>
      <description>Navitas Semiconductor Corp of Torrance, CA, USA — which provides GaNFast gallium nitride (GaN) and GeneSiC silicon carbide (SiC) power semiconductors — and ASIC/ASSP and power solutions provider Cyient Semiconductor Pte Ltd of Hyderabad, India have announced a strategic long-term partnership intended to advance the adoption of GaN technology in India and establish a complete end-to-end GaN ecosystem...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">[object Object]</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:08:15 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Nvidia Set to Win US Approval to Export H200 AI Chips to China</title>
      <link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-08/nvidia-set-to-win-us-approval-to-export-h200-ai-chips-to-china</link>
      <description>The Trump administration is poised to allow Nvidia Corp. to sell its H200 artificial intelligence chip to China, according to people familiar with the matter, a move that would mark a major lobbying win for the world’s most valuable company and potentially let it regain billions of dollars of business lost in a key global market.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">[object Object]</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:07:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Environmental groups call for halt to new data center construction</title>
      <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/12/08/environmental-groups-call-for-halt-to-new-data-center-construction/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/gettyimages-502033199.jpg?resize=1200,640&quot; alt=&quot;gettyimages-502033199.jpg?resize=1200,64&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;More than 230 organizations signed a public letter urging members of Congress to take action.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">[object Object]</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:52:35 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>TSMC’s Advanced Packaging Production Lines Are So ‘Bottled Up’ That the Firm Is Now Looking to Outsource Orders to Meet Demand</title>
      <link>https://wccftech.com/tsmcs-advanced-packaging-production-lines-are-so-bottled-up-that-the-firm-is-now-looking-to-outsource-orders/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/tsmcs-advanced-packaging-production-lines-are-so-bottled-up-that-the-firm-is-now-looking-to-outsource-orders/&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;419&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/11/TSMC-1-728x419.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TSMC could surpass Apple in market value by 2030, predicts analyst&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;TSMC&apos;s advanced packaging capacity is &apos;fully booked&apos; at the moment, which is a huge concern for the AI industry, but it appears that the Taiwan giant has a strategy in sight. TSMC&apos;s &apos;CoWoS&apos; Production Lines Have No Room For Further Orders, As the Firm Now Relies on Outsourcing Advanced packaging has been the &apos;holy grail&apos; for manufacturers when it comes to combining multiple chiplets to scale up the performance of their AI chips, which is why solutions like TSMC&apos;s CoWoS are experiencing peak interest from companies such as NVIDIA, AMD, Google, Apple, MediaTek, and many more. However, based on supply […]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read full article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/tsmcs-advanced-packaging-production-lines-are-so-bottled-up-that-the-firm-is-now-looking-to-outsource-orders/&quot;&gt;https://wccftech.com/tsmcs-advanced-packaging-production-lines-are-so-bottled-up-that-the-firm-is-now-looking-to-outsource-orders/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">[object Object]</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>16-Core Hygon C86 CPU Reportedly Boasts 3.0 GHz Boost Clock And 95 W TDP</title>
      <link>https://wccftech.com/16-core-hygon-c86-cpu-reportedly-boasts-3-0-ghz-boost-clock-and-95-tdp/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/16-core-hygon-c86-cpu-reportedly-boasts-3-0-ghz-boost-clock-and-95-tdp/&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;410&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Hygon-C86-4G-CPU-728x410.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Two Hygon processors are displayed with the text &apos;3.0 GHz&apos; against a green wavy background.&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;X86 instruction-compatible Hygon C86 CPU that reportedly delivered on par performance with Intel&apos;s 13th gen processors in MT workloads, can boost up to 3.0 GHz. Leak Suggests Hygon C86 Could Hit 3.0 GHz Boost and 95 W TDP, Making it a True-Efficiency+Performance x86 Contender The last time we looked at the Chinese-made Hygon C86 series, it appeared inside the Thunderobot gaming PCs. The report showcased performance numbers that matched Intel Raptor Lake&apos;s Core i7 SKUs in multi-threaded benchmarks. Despite weaker single-threaded results, the chip demonstrated China&apos;s domestic x86 designs that are evolving quite fast enough to compete with recent processor […]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read full article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/16-core-hygon-c86-cpu-reportedly-boasts-3-0-ghz-boost-clock-and-95-tdp/&quot;&gt;https://wccftech.com/16-core-hygon-c86-cpu-reportedly-boasts-3-0-ghz-boost-clock-and-95-tdp/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">[object Object]</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Apple Chip Guru, Johny Srouji, Declares He Is Not Planning On “Leaving Anytime Soon”</title>
      <link>https://wccftech.com/apple-chip-guru-johny-srouji-declares-he-is-not-planning-on-leaving-anytime-soon/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/apple-chip-guru-johny-srouji-declares-he-is-not-planning-on-leaving-anytime-soon/&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Apple-Johny-Srouji-1-728x485.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A person in a blue shirt walks through a modern, high-tech laboratory with multiple workstations and computer screens.&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a dramatic turn of events, Apple&apos;s head of custom silicon and the Senior Vice President of its Hardware Technologies division, Johny Srouji, has publicly declared now that he would stay put at Apple, as per the leaked anecdote of a meeting earlier today. Johny Srouji: &quot;I love my team, and I love my job at Apple&quot; Bloomberg&apos;s Mark Gurman is out with a scoop today, detailing the minutes of a meeting at Apple earlier today, where the Cupertino giant&apos;s head of custom silicon, Johny Srouji, has reportedly renounced any intention of leaving Apple by declaring: &quot;I love my team, […]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read full article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/apple-chip-guru-johny-srouji-declares-he-is-not-planning-on-leaving-anytime-soon/&quot;&gt;https://wccftech.com/apple-chip-guru-johny-srouji-declares-he-is-not-planning-on-leaving-anytime-soon/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">[object Object]</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:27:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>IQE extends multi-year strategic supply agreement with Lumentum</title>
      <link>https://www.semiconductor-today.com/news_items/2025/dec/iqe-lumentum-081225.shtml</link>
      <description>Epiwafer and substrate maker IQE plc of Cardiff, Wales, UK has signed a multi-year extension to its strategic agreement with Lumentum Holdings Inc of San Jose, CA, USA (which designs and makes photonics products for optical networks and lasers for industrial and consumer markets) for the supply of epiwafers supporting advanced sensing technologies...</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">[object Object]</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:09:27 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>New ultra-thin nanomesh electrodes enable breathable &apos;electronic skin&apos;</title>
      <link>https://techxplore.com/news/2025-12-ultra-thin-nanomesh-electrodes-enable.html</link>
      <description>Researchers have successfully developed a high-resolution electronic skin (e-skin) device on a breathable (nanomesh) substrate using transfer technology employed in semiconductor manufacturing.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">[object Object]</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:06:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>A geometric recipe for stabilizing atomically thin metals</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-12-geometric-recipe-stabilizing-atomically-thin.html</link>
      <description>Metallenes are atomically thin metals whose unique properties make them extremely promising for nanoscale applications. However, their extreme thinness makes them also flimsy.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">[object Object]</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 19:02:06 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Meta will let Facebook and Instagram users in the EU share less data</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/social-media/meta-will-let-facebook-and-instagram-users-in-the-eu-share-less-data-183535897.html?src=rss</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meta will soon allow Facebook and Instagram users in the European Union to choose to share less data and see less personalized ads on the platform, the European Commission &lt;a href=&quot;https://digital-markets-act.ec.europa.eu/meta-commits-give-eu-users-choice-personalised-ads-under-dma-2025-12-08_en&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt;. The change will begin to roll out in January, according to the regulator. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;This is the first time that such a choice is offered on Meta&apos;s social networks,&quot; the commission said in a statement. &quot;Meta will give users the effective choice between: consenting to share all their data and seeing fully personalised advertising, and opting to share less personal data for an experience with more limited personalised advertising.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The move from Meta comes after the European Commission had fined the company €200 million over its ad-free subscription plans in the EU, which the regulator deemed &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/eu-criticizes-metas-privacy-for-cash-business-model-103042528.html&quot;&gt;consent or pay&lt;/a&gt;.&quot; Meta began offering ad-free subscriptions to EU users &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/facebook-and-instagram-will-start-offering-ad-free-plans-in-europe-in-november-141650104.html&quot;&gt;in 2023&lt;/a&gt;, and later &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/meta-cuts-the-price-of-its-ad-free-plan-by-40-percent-in-a-bid-to-sate-eu-regulators-174926790.html&quot;&gt;lowered the price&lt;/a&gt; of the plans in response to criticism from the commission. Those plans haven&apos;t been very popular, however, with one Meta executive &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/what-weve-learned-from-ftc-v-meta-antitrust-trial-162048138.html&quot;&gt;admitting&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year that there&apos;s been &quot;very little interest&quot; from users. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a statement, a Meta spokesperson said that &quot;we acknowledge&quot; the European Commission&apos;s statement. &quot;Personalized ads are vital for Europe’s economy — last year, Meta’s ads were linked to €213 billion in economic activity and supported 1.44 million jobs across the EU.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/social-media/meta-will-let-facebook-and-instagram-users-in-the-eu-share-less-data-183535897.html?src=rss</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">[object Object]</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:47:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>India Paves Dual RISC-V Tracks with C-DAC and Startup Silicon</title>
      <link>https://www.eetimes.com/india-paves-dual-risc-v-tracks-with-c-dac-and-startup-silicon/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A global move toward customizable processor architectures is creating room for India to push into RISC-V, with government labs and young chip firms taking different paths. India is now coupling a&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">[object Object]</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:24:57 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>