<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Professional News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Curated articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 03:52:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>

    <item>
      <title>SK hynix Honored with Two Major Titles at GSA Awards 2025</title>
      <link>https://news.skhynix.com/sk-hynix-honored-with-two-major-titles-at-gsa-awards-2025/</link>
      <description>&lt;div style=&quot;height:20px;&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News Highlights&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;div style=&quot;height:30px;&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;div style=&quot;border:none;background:#f5f5f5;height:auto;padding-left:10px;padding-top:30px;padding-bottom:5px;&quot;&gt;
 
&lt;ul style=&quot;color:#000;font-size:18px;padding-left:10px;padding-right:20px;&quot;&gt;
 
&lt;li&gt;SK hynix recognized as the top financially managed semiconductor company by GSA&lt;/li&gt;
 
&lt;li&gt;Company named “Best Financially Managed Semiconductor Company(Achieving Greater than $1 Billion in Annual Sales)” and “Outstanding Asia-Pacific Semiconductor Company” simultaneously&lt;/li&gt;
 
&lt;li&gt;Accelerates recovery from market downturn leveraging world-class HBM leadership; Global management performance recognized&lt;/li&gt;
 
&lt;li&gt;Reflects company’s technology leadership and customer-centric execution&lt;/li&gt;
 
&lt;li&gt;SK Chairman Chey Tae-won emphasizes: “Technological competitiveness must remain unwavering in challenging times”&lt;/li&gt;
 
&lt;li&gt;Commits to driving new customer value and leading global AI market growth as a “Full-Stack AI Memory Creator”&lt;/li&gt;
 
&lt;/ul&gt;
 
&lt;/div&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;div style=&quot;height:30px;&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seoul, December 7, 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;div style=&quot;height:30px;&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;p&gt;SK hynix Inc. (or “the company”, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.skhynix.com/eng/main.do&quot;&gt;www.skhynix.com&lt;/a&gt;) announced today that it has been named the winner of the Best Financially Managed Semiconductor Company Award (Achieving Greater than $1 Billion in Annual Sales)&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt; and the Outstanding Asia-Pacific Semiconductor Company Award&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt; at the Global Semiconductor Alliance(GSA)&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Awards 2025, held on December 4 PST in Santa Clara, California.&lt;/p&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;div style=&quot;height:10px;&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;p style=&quot;color:#555555;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Best Financially Managed Semiconductor Company Award&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; A category recognizing public semiconductor companies based on financial soundness and operational efficiency. Awards are presented in two categories — annual sales over $1 billion and annual sales under $1 billion — and are considered among the most authoritative honors in the global semiconductor industry. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p style=&quot;color:#555555;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;Outstanding Asia-Pacific Semiconductor Company Award:&lt;/strong&gt; A special category recognizing semiconductor companies headquartered in the Asia-Pacific region based on comprehensive evaluations including product excellence, business vision, leadership, and market success. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p style=&quot;color:#555555;font-size:14px;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;GSA(Global Semiconductor Alliance):&lt;/strong&gt; A global CEO-level semiconductor organization serving as a hub for technological information sharing across more than 25 countries and over 250 corporate members.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 

 

 

 

 

 
&lt;p&gt;The GSA Awards, organized annually since 1996, are regarded as the most prestigious honors in the global semiconductor sector, recognizing outstanding performance in leadership, financial results and industry reputation. SK hynix secured its second win in the financial management category following 2017, and its first recognition as the top Asia-Pacific semiconductor company. The dual achievement reinforces the company’s reputation as a leading global technology innovator.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;While the semiconductor industry faced a severe downturn just two years ago, the company has been the fastest to rebound thanks to its advanced AI memory technologies including HBM. This performance has resulted in global recognition for its operational excellence and financial execution. SK hynix plans to continue building sustainable growth with its dominant leadership in the AI memory market.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The awards reflect the company’s proactive delivery of groundbreaking HBM solutions and its steadfast commitment to customer-centric performance in surging global AI demand. SK Chairman Chey Tae-won has consistently emphasized that securing technological competitiveness must remain unwavering, especially during challenging times. This long-term focus on technology investment and global cooperation network has contributed to the company’s improved performance and reinforced financial health.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Driven by this strategy, SK hynix has recorded historic performance throughout 2025. For the first three quarters, the company reported revenue of 64 trillion won and operating profit of 28 trillion won in total, positioning it well to surpass its previous full-year earnings record set in 2024 (66 trillion won in revenue and 23 trillion won in operating profit).&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Financial health has also significantly strengthened. As of the end of the third quarter, cash and cash equivalents reached 27.9 trillion won, up 10.9 trillion won quarter-over-quarter, while interest bearing debt decreased to 24.1 trillion won— successfully transitioning into a net cash position of approximately 4 trillion won.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;To secure long-term leadership in AI memory, SK hynix is accelerating major investments. The Cheongju M15X fab, which opened its cleanroom earlier than planned in October, is on track to begin HBM mass production in the first half of next year. Construction of the first fab in the Yongin Semiconductor Cluster, launched in February, is also progressing ahead of schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;With its recent financial achievements and continued expansion, SK hynix is expected to further solidify its AI memory leadership going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;SK hynix was represented at the ceremony by Justin Kim, President &amp;amp; Head of AI Infra at SK hynix, and Sungsoo Ryu, President of SK hynix America. “It is a great honor to receive this award.” Kim said, “We will continue to lead the market and create new value for customers as a Full-Stack AI Memory Creator, driving growth across the global AI ecosystem.”&lt;/p&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;div style=&quot;height:30px;&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About SK hynix Inc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;div style=&quot;height:30px;&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;p&gt;SK hynix Inc., headquartered in Korea, is the world’s top tier semiconductor supplier offering Dynamic Random Access Memory chips (“DRAM”) and flash memory chips (“NAND flash”) for a wide range of distinguished customers globally. The Company’s shares are traded on the Korea Exchange, and the Global Depository shares are listed on the Luxembourg Stock Exchange. Further information about SK hynix is available at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.skhynix.com/eng/main.do&quot;&gt;www.skhynix.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.skhynix.com/&quot;&gt;news.skhynix.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;div style=&quot;height:30px;&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;div style=&quot;height:30px;&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;p&gt;SK hynix Inc.&lt;br&gt;Global Public Relations&lt;/p&gt;
 

 

 

 
&lt;p&gt;Technical Leader&lt;br&gt;Sooyeon Lee, Minseok Jang&lt;br&gt;E-Mail: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:global_pr@skhynix.com&quot;&gt;global_pr@skhynix.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.skhynix.com/sk-hynix-honored-with-two-major-titles-at-gsa-awards-2025/&quot;&gt;SK hynix Honored with Two Major Titles at GSA Awards 2025&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.skhynix.com&quot;&gt;SK hynix Newsroom&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 23:41:23 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Apple&apos;s Johny Srouji could continue the company&apos;s executive exodus, according to report</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/apples-johny-srouji-could-continue-the-companys-executive-exodus-according-to-report-200750252.html?src=rss</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Apple&apos;s Johny Srouji may be the latest company executive to seek greener pastures, according to a report from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-06/apple-rocked-by-executive-departures-with-johny-srouji-at-risk-of-leaving-next&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The report said that Srouji, Apple&apos;s senior vice president of hardware technologies, told Tim Cook that he is &quot;seriously considering leaving in the near future.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;While the report didn&apos;t mention if Srouji has another job lined up, &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&apos;s sources claimed that he wants to join another company if he leaves Apple. Srouji joined the company in 2008 to develop Apple&apos;s first in-house system-on-a-chip and eventually led the transition to Apple silicon.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Srouji leaves Apple, he would be the latest in a string of departures of longtime execs. At the start of the month, Apple announced that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2025/12/john-giannandrea-to-retire-from-apple/&quot;&gt;John Giannandrea&lt;/a&gt;, the company&apos;s senior vice president for machine learning and AI strategy, would be retiring from his role in spring 2026. A couple of days later, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-03/apple-design-executive-alan-dye-poached-by-meta-in-major-coup?embedded-checkout=true&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; reported that the company&apos;s head of interface design, Alan Dye, would be leaving for a role at Meta. Adding to those exits, Apple also &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/newsroom/2025/12/apple-announces-executive-transitions/&quot;&gt;revealed&lt;/a&gt; that Kate Adams, who has been Apple&apos;s general counsel since 2017, and Lisa Jackson, vice president for Environment, Policy, and Social Initiatives, will both be leaving in early 2026.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The shakeup at the executive level comes after &lt;em&gt;Bloomberg&lt;/em&gt;&apos;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-11-23/apple-ios-27-snow-leopard-like-quality-focus-ai-features-tim-cook-retirement-mibq7jv8&quot;&gt;Mark Gurman&lt;/a&gt; previously reported that Cook may not be preparing for his own departure as CEO next year. Gurman&apos;s prediction counters a report from the &lt;em&gt;Financial Times&lt;/em&gt; that claimed that Apple was accelerating &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/apple-is-reportedly-getting-ready-to-replace-tim-cook-as-early-as-next-year-171407974.html&quot;&gt;succession plans&lt;/a&gt; for Cook with an expected stepping down sometime next year.&lt;/p&gt;This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/apples-johny-srouji-could-continue-the-companys-executive-exodus-according-to-report-200750252.html?src=rss</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 20:10:30 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Apple’s chip chief might be the next exec to leave</title>
      <link>https://www.theverge.com/news/839700/apples-chip-chief-might-be-the-next-exec-to-leave</link>
      <description> 
 
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.theverge.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2025/08/STK071_APPLE_D.jpg?quality=90&amp;amp;strip=all&amp;amp;crop=0,0,100,100&quot;&gt; 
	 
		 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bloomberg’s&lt;/em&gt; Mark Gurman is reporting that Johny Srouji, senior vice president of hardware technologies, told Tim Cook he is “seriously considering” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-06/apple-rocked-by-executive-departures-with-johny-srouji-at-risk-of-leaving-next&quot;&gt;leaving Apple&lt;/a&gt; for another company in the near future. It was reported in October that Srouji was “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/798258/apple-executive-reshuffling-eddy-cue-johnny-srouji&quot;&gt;evaluating his future at the tech giant&lt;/a&gt;.” While nothing is confirmed, it seems the executive is leaning towards not having a future at Cupertino.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
&lt;p&gt;If Srouji leaves, he would be just the latest in a string of high-profile shakeups in the company’s C-suite. COO Jeff Williams &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/701576/apple-coo-jeff-williams-retiring-sabih-khan&quot;&gt;announced his retirement&lt;/a&gt; in July, which led to some shifting of roles. But things have only accelerated in December, with AI chief John Giannandrea &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/835466/apple-ai-chief-john-giannandrea-steps-down-siri&quot;&gt;stepping down&lt;/a&gt;, policy lead Lisa Jackson and general counsel Kate Adams announcing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/838712/apple-policy-lead-lisa-jackson-retiring&quot;&gt;plans to retire&lt;/a&gt;, and UI design lead Alan Dye &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/837654/apple-meta-alan-dye-designer&quot;&gt;departing for Meta&lt;/a&gt;, all in the last few days.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
&lt;p&gt;Apple has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/24/24351391/apple-change-ai-team-siri-upgrades-kim-vorrath&quot;&gt;struggled somewhat&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/669238/apple-siri-llm-ai-revamp&quot;&gt;find its footing&lt;/a&gt; as the industry further embraces AI. Now Tim Cook is tasked with trying to stem the bleeding, while being subject to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/news/821691/tim-cook-step-down-apple-ceo-next-year&quot;&gt;rumors&lt;/a&gt; of his own departure. Gurman, who is usually reliable, has said those rumors are &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/news/newsletters/2025-11-23/apple-ios-27-snow-leopard-like-quality-focus-ai-features-tim-cook-retirement-mibq7jv8&quot;&gt;premature&lt;/a&gt;, but it still adds to the uncertainty surrounding what is typically one of the more stable companies in Silicon Valley. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 20:04:53 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>OneXPlayer Readies First Panther Lake-Based Gaming Handheld As Spotted On Geekbench</title>
      <link>https://wccftech.com/onexplayer-readies-first-panther-lake-based-gaming-handheld-as-spotted-on-geekbench/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/onexplayer-readies-first-panther-lake-based-gaming-handheld-as-spotted-on-geekbench/&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;410&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/OneXPlayer-X1-338H-728x410.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The ONE XPLAYER X1 gaming handheld is shown with detachable controllers and the text &apos;Ultra 5 338H&apos;.&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Handheld manufacturers already look interested in Panther Lake for their gaming devices, and the first one is OneXPlayer. OneXPlayer X1 Gaming Handheld With Intel Core Ultra 5 338H Spotted on Geekbench; Handheld to Boast 32 GB Memory A plethora of benchmarks for Intel Panther Lake chips have leaked over the past weeks, and we have seen their iGPUs perform competitively or even better than RDNDA 3.5-based iGPUs on AMD Strix Point. While it took quite some time for handheld manufacturers to start adopting the Strix Point chips in their handhelds, Panther Lake-based handhelds should be available as soon as the […]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read full article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/onexplayer-readies-first-panther-lake-based-gaming-handheld-as-spotted-on-geekbench/&quot;&gt;https://wccftech.com/onexplayer-readies-first-panther-lake-based-gaming-handheld-as-spotted-on-geekbench/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 19:44:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Apple’s Chip Guru &amp; SVP Of Hardware Technologies, Johny Srouji, Is Reportedly Considering Leaving, With The Company Making Massive Efforts To Retain Him</title>
      <link>https://wccftech.com/apple-chip-guru-johny-srouji-wants-to-leave-company/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/apple-chip-guru-johny-srouji-wants-to-leave-company/&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;437&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Johny-Srouji-728x437.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Apple&apos;s SVP of Hardware Technologies, Johny Srouji, wants to leave the company&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The tightly-knitted integration between Apple’s hardware and software would not have been possible without Johny Srouji, the technology giant’s Senior Vice President of Hardware Technologies and with the executive contemplating his departure, it could be the biggest blow received to the trillion-dollar titan. Fortunately, a new report states that Apple is doing everything in its power to keep him, as they should, given how valuable he is to the company and its mission. Johny Srouji is not seeking retirement but wishes to pursue his career in another company; Meta could be his next destination, given how the latter is poaching […]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read full article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/apple-chip-guru-johny-srouji-wants-to-leave-company/&quot;&gt;https://wccftech.com/apple-chip-guru-johny-srouji-wants-to-leave-company/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 19:44:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>