<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Professional News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Curated articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 11:44:35 GMT</lastBuildDate>

    <item>
      <title>Google’s TPUs May Deliver ‘Impressive’ Performance, But One Overlooked Bottleneck Could Bring External Scaling to a Halt Before It Even Begins</title>
      <link>https://wccftech.com/google-tpu-may-deliver-impressive-performance-but-one-overlooked-bottleneck-could-bring-external-scaling-to-a-halt/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/google-tpu-may-deliver-impressive-performance-but-one-overlooked-bottleneck-could-bring-external-scaling-to-a-halt/&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Ironwood.original-728x485.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A reflective close-up of a square chip labeled Ironwood with a blurred bokeh background.&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Google&apos;s TPUs have made headlines across the AI world, following reports of external adoption; however, there&apos;s an angle to this that might prove to be a significant constraint. Google&apos;s &apos;Ironwood&apos; AI Chips Are Seeing Immense Market Spotlight, But There&apos;s a Problem With This The interest around ASICs is massive in today&apos;s world of AI computing, mainly since it is believed that in the next layer of AI application, which is inferencing, chips like Google&apos;s TPUs will dominate with better TCOs and performance capabilities. Following the introduction of Google&apos;s 7th-generation Ironwood TPUs, companies like Meta and Anthropic showed interest in integrating […]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read full article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/google-tpu-may-deliver-impressive-performance-but-one-overlooked-bottleneck-could-bring-external-scaling-to-a-halt/&quot;&gt;https://wccftech.com/google-tpu-may-deliver-impressive-performance-but-one-overlooked-bottleneck-could-bring-external-scaling-to-a-halt/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:33:26 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>CAFC Gives Targeted Ads Patent Owner Another Shot at Meta Due to District Court Error</title>
      <link>https://ipwatchdog.com/2025/12/07/cafc-gives-targeted-ads-patent-owner-shot-meta-district-court-error/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ipwatchdog.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/precedent-deinition-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;precedent-deinition-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit (CAFC) on Friday vacated and remanded a district court’s decision in favor of Meta, rejecting the court’s finding that patent owner Adnexus had failed to state a plausible claim for direct infringement. The decision was precedential and authored by Judge Stark, with whom Judges Taranto and Prost joined.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipwatchdog.com/2025/12/07/cafc-gives-targeted-ads-patent-owner-shot-meta-district-court-error/&quot;&gt;CAFC Gives Targeted Ads Patent Owner Another Shot at Meta Due to District Court Error&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipwatchdog.com&quot;&gt;IPWatchdog.com | Patents &amp;amp; Intellectual Property Law&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 17:36:58 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Apple&apos;s chief chip architect for the last decade has reportedly talked to CEO Tim Cook about leaving</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/apples-chief-chip-architect-for-the-last-decade-has-reportedly-talked-to-ceo-tim-cook-about-leaving</link>
      <description>Johny Srouji, the man behind development of Apple&apos;s processors in the latest iPhones, Macs, and Watches, is reportedly pondering leaving the company.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:44:37 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Samsung’s 4nm Process Has Witnessed Yield Improvements In The 60-70% Range, Enabling It To Reportedly Win A $100 Million Order To Develop An Omni Processing Unit For A U.S. Firm</title>
      <link>https://wccftech.com/samsung-4nm-yields-improvement-lands-100-million-order-to-make-omni-processing-unit/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/samsung-4nm-yields-improvement-lands-100-million-order-to-make-omni-processing-unit/&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;410&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Samsung-chip-plant-728x410.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Samsung&apos;s improved 4nm yields lands it orders to build an Omni Processing Unit (OPU) for a U.S. firm&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The struggles experienced by Samsung’s foundry business could be on their way out because the 4nm process, which was previously said to be a nightmare for the Korean giant, is slowly stabilizing, with the latest report mentioning a 60-70 percent yield range. This improvement has landed a major order for Samsung on its older technology, with a U.S. firm requiring an Omni Processing Unit (OPU) and having pre-ordered more than $100 million of these chips. The 4nm node has haunted Samsung due to less-than-stellar yields, but improving its older-generation processes can bring it closer to achieving profitability for the foundry […]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read full article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/samsung-4nm-yields-improvement-lands-100-million-order-to-make-omni-processing-unit/&quot;&gt;https://wccftech.com/samsung-4nm-yields-improvement-lands-100-million-order-to-make-omni-processing-unit/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:33:26 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>The iPhone 18 may finally add a camera feature that Samsung introduced on its flagship phones in 2021</title>
      <link>https://www.techradar.com/phones/iphone/the-iphone-18-may-finally-add-a-camera-feature-that-samsung-introduced-on-its-flagship-phones-in-2021</link>
      <description>Apple has long been rumored to be adding an under-display camera to the iPhone, and it could happen in 2026.</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 16:30:52 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>With one small step for AI, Chinese scientists make giant leap for humanity</title>
      <link>https://www.scmp.com/news/china/science/article/3335515/one-small-step-ai-chinese-scientists-make-giant-leap-humanity?utm_source=rss_feed</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.i-scmp.com/sites/default/files/styles/og_image_scmp_generic/public/d8/images/canvas/2025/12/07/ec2f3c0a-ef55-45fb-9cf3-efc0f20db5a8_e598818c.jpg?itok=yBidECmd&amp;amp;v=1765107242&quot; alt=&quot;ec2f3c0a-ef55-45fb-9cf3-efc0f20db5a8_e59&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Imagine a robot that could tie your shoelaces to the perfect degree of tightness, or a robotic hand capable of performing abdominal surgery and then suturing the wound with impeccable precision.  
You might assume these feats would rely on complex electronic sensors, and yet a breakthrough by Chinese scientists has made it possible for robots to rival the skill of experienced surgeons – even with their “eyes closed” – using just a simple knot.  
The achievement, by an interdisciplinary team from...</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 14:07:14 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>