<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Professional News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Curated articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 16:03:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>

    <item>
      <title>TSMC could be inching closer to making &apos;all American&apos; chips — report says it is accelerating an advanced packaging facility in Arizona</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/semiconductors/tsmc-could-be-inching-closer-to-making-all-american-chips-report-says-it-is-accelerating-an-advanced-packaging-facility-in-arizona</link>
      <description>TSMC may be accelerating its advanced packaging facility in Arizona to package the first processors as early as 2028, ahead of its partner Amkor.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 15:55:41 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>TSMC claims 4.2X efficiency gain over a decade from N7 to A14 fabrication process</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/semiconductors/tsmc-claims-4-2x-efficiency-gain-over-a-decade-from-n7-to-a14-fabrication-process</link>
      <description>TSMC clarifies A14 specifications: Even more performance, but better tools might be needed to extract the full potential of the latest process technologies.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 14:47:51 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Intel Arc Battlemage “BMG-G31” GPU Receives Brand New Support By The Chipmaker Itself, Is Big Battlemage Finally Ready For Launch?</title>
      <link>https://wccftech.com/intel-arc-battlemage-bmg-g31-gpu-brand-new-support-big-battlemage-finally-ready/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/intel-arc-battlemage-bmg-g31-gpu-brand-new-support-big-battlemage-finally-ready/&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;409&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Intel-Arc-Battlemage-BMG-G31-GPU-728x409.png&quot; alt=&quot;Intel Arc Battlemage &amp;quot;BMG-G31&amp;quot; GPU Recieves Brand New Support By The Chipmaker Itself, Is Big Battlemage Finally Ready For Launch? 1&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Intel has just added the latest support for its Arc Battlemage &quot;BMG-G31&quot; GPU, hinting that the launch should be closer than we think. Intel&apos;s Big Battlemage &quot;Arc BMG-G31&quot; GPU Sees Brand New Support, Launching Soon? Rumors around the launch of Intel&apos;s Big Arc Battlemage GPU, the BMG-G31, have been circling the web for a good year or so. The launch was expected soon after the BMG-G21 GPU, which was introduced on Intel&apos;s Arc B580 and Arc B570 graphics cards. The rumored Arc B770 was expected to launch earlier this year, but we are at the end of 2025, and we […]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read full article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/intel-arc-battlemage-bmg-g31-gpu-brand-new-support-big-battlemage-finally-ready/&quot;&gt;https://wccftech.com/intel-arc-battlemage-bmg-g31-gpu-brand-new-support-big-battlemage-finally-ready/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:44:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Two GTX 580s in SLI are responsible for the AI we have today — Nvidia&apos;s Huang revealed that the invention of deep learning began with two flagship Fermi GPUs in 2012</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/artificial-intelligence/two-gtx-580s-in-sli-are-responsible-for-the-ai-we-have-today-nvidias-huang-revealed-that-the-invention-of-deep-learning-began-with-two-flagship-fermi-gpus-in-2012</link>
      <description>Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang revealed in a recent Joe Rogan podcast that the inventors behind deep learning ran the world&apos;s first machine learning network on a pair of GTX 580s in SLI in 2012.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 13:09:18 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Intel’s 2026 EMIB Breakout: 18A-P Opens the Door for Global Chipmakers</title>
      <link>https://techovedas.com/intels-2026-emib-breakout-18a-p-opens-the-door-for-global-chipmakers/</link>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;Intel’s push into advanced packaging and leading-edge nodes is accelerating. Interest in Intel’s &lt;strong&gt;EMIB (Embedded Multi-die Interconnect Bridge)&lt;/strong&gt; technology is growing across the semiconductor industry—driven by chip shortages, AI compute demands, and the search for alternatives to &lt;a href=&quot;https://techovedas.com/17-14-billion-tsmc-invests-yuan-in-innolux-factory-to-double-advanced-packaging-capacity-by-2025/&quot;&gt;TSMC’s CoWoS.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;At the &lt;strong&gt;UBS Global Technology and AI Conference 2025&lt;/strong&gt;, Intel Corporate VP &lt;strong&gt;John Pitzer&lt;/strong&gt; outlined how EMIB, 18A-P, 18A-PT, and 14A are evolving into crucial pillars of Intel’s re-entry into the contract manufacturing race. With Google, Meta, and top fabless customers evaluating Intel’s roadmap, the second half of 2026 is shaping up as a transformative period for &lt;strong&gt;Intel Foundry Services (IFS)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techovedas.com/intels-18a-vs-tsmcs-n2-next-generation-process-nodes/&quot;&gt;techovedas.com/intels-18a-vs-tsmcs-n2-next-generation-process-nodes/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h2&gt;5-Point Quick Summary&lt;/h2&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;ol&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EMIB ramps in 2H26&lt;/strong&gt; as industry adoption grows, including Google’s 2027 TPU.&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intel expands packaging capacity&lt;/strong&gt; with Amkor (South Korea) and Project Pelican (Malaysia).&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18A yields improving steadily&lt;/strong&gt;, Panther Lake remains on track with internal tile production.&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18A-P and 18A-PT open to external clients&lt;/strong&gt;, strengthening IFS’s chiplet-based strategy.&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14A progresses strongly&lt;/strong&gt;, with fabless customers expected to make design decisions between 2H26–1H27.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ol&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techovedas.com/tsmc-a16-takes-on-intel-14a-and-samsung-sf1-4-in-the-angstrom-arena/&quot;&gt;techovedas.com/tsmc-a16-takes-on-intel-14a-and-samsung-sf1-4-in-the-angstrom-arena/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h2&gt;Why EMIB Is Becoming Central to Intel’s Strategy&lt;/h2&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;EMIB was initially seen as a niche alternative to fan-out and 2.5D packaging. But as TSMC’s &lt;strong&gt;CoWoS capacity tightened in 2023–2024&lt;/strong&gt;, demand spilled over to Intel. What began as overflow interest has now, according to Pitzer, shifted to &lt;strong&gt;technology-driven adoption&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h3&gt;Key reasons EMIB is gaining momentum:&lt;/h3&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;ul&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scalable multi-die integration&lt;/strong&gt; for CPUs, GPUs, and AI accelerators&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Higher interconnect density&lt;/strong&gt; than CoWoS in several configurations&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lower thermal resistance&lt;/strong&gt;, critical for high-power AI tiles&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better modularity&lt;/strong&gt; for chiplet-based systems&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early production success&lt;/strong&gt; in Intel’s own server platforms&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;TrendForce reports that Intel already uses EMIB across &lt;strong&gt;Sapphire Rapids&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Granite Rapids&lt;/strong&gt;, demonstrating production maturity.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;The next wave is even bigger:&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;ul&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google plans to implement EMIB in its 2027 TPU v9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meta is evaluating EMIB for future MTIA accelerators&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;These wins would deliver a serious credibility boost to IFS.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/techovedas/&quot;&gt;Follow us on Linkedin for everything around Semiconductors &amp;amp; AI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h2&gt;Intel Expands EMIB Capacity Across South Korea and Malaysia&lt;/h2&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;In parallel with industry adoption, Intel is scaling its EMIB manufacturing footprint faster than expected.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two major expansions are already underway:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;img width=&quot;1024&quot; height=&quot;726&quot; src=&quot;https://techovedas.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/image-17-1024x726.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h4&gt;1. EMIB at Amkor’s Songdo K5 (South Korea)&lt;/h4&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;ul&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;ETNews reports Intel has established EMIB processes at Amkor&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;This marks Intel’s &lt;strong&gt;first-ever outsourcing of high-end packaging&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;It gives Intel a scalable partner to support large AI customers&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h4&gt;2. Project Pelican (Malaysia)&lt;/h4&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;TechPowerUp highlights Intel’s nearly complete &lt;strong&gt;$7 billion packaging mega-complex&lt;/strong&gt;, which will handle both &lt;strong&gt;EMIB&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Foveros&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;ul&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;This will become one of Intel’s most advanced OSAT-like facilities&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;It strengthens supply chain localization across Southeast Asia&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;Together, these moves are designed to ensure that when demand spikes in 2026, Intel will not face the bottlenecks seen by its competitors.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techovedas.com/intel-18a-debuts-limited-q3-shipments-and-panther-lake-launch-on-october-9&quot;&gt;techovedas.com/intel-18a-debuts-limited-q3-shipments-and-panther-lake-launch-on-october-9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h2&gt;18A Progress: Not Fully Optimal Yet, But Rapidly Improving&lt;/h2&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;Intel’s biggest near-term challenge remains yield. Pitzer acknowledged that &lt;strong&gt;18A yields “aren’t yet optimal”&lt;/strong&gt;, but improvements under&lt;a href=&quot;https://techovedas.com/lip-bu-tan-as-new-intel-ceo-a-power-move-that-could-change-everything/&quot;&gt; CEO &lt;strong&gt;Lip-Bu Tan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are accelerating.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;According to TechPowerUp:&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;ul&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techovedas.com/intel-18a-debuts-limited-q3-shipments-and-panther-lake-launch-on-october-9/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panther Lake&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;/a&gt; Intel’s first major 18A client product, remains on schedule&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;Yield gains of &lt;strong&gt;7% per month&lt;/strong&gt; could sustain full-volume production&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;Costs per unit should remain stable as yield improves&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;This is significant because 18A represents Intel’s first attempt to match—and in some scenarios surpass—&lt;a href=&quot;https://techovedas.com/100-billion-tsmc-and-samsung-explore-chip-mega-factories-in-uae/&quot;&gt;TSMC and Samsung &lt;/a&gt;on process leadership.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techovedas.com/techovedas.com/100-billion-tsmc-and-samsung-explore-chip-mega-factories-in-uae/&quot;&gt;/techovedas.com/100-billion-tsmc-and-samsung-explore-chip-mega-factories-in-uae/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h2&gt;18A-P and 18A-PT Move Toward External Customers&lt;/h2&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;While 18A is primarily internal, Intel is opening &lt;strong&gt;18A-P&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;18A-PT&lt;/strong&gt; to external chipmakers.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h4&gt;What’s the difference?&lt;/h4&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;ul&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18A-P&lt;/strong&gt; = enhanced 18A variant for both Intel and external clients&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18A-PT&lt;/strong&gt; = the base die for advanced packaging (multi-die architectures)&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;This aligns directly with IFS’s business model:&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;ul&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;Intel wants to become the world’s &lt;strong&gt;leading advanced packaging foundry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;External customers can design compute tiles on 18A-P&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;These tiles can then be integrated via &lt;strong&gt;EMIB or Foveros&lt;/strong&gt; on 18A-PT&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;This approach mirrors how TSMC handles N3 and CoWoS, but Intel aims to differentiate with tighter chiplet-level integration.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h2&gt;Intel Accelerates In-House Production for Panther Lake and Nova Lake&lt;/h2&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;A major strategic shift is happening internally. Intel wants to bring more compute tile production back in-house to improve performance, cost control, and supply chain reliability.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;According to the conference transcript:&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;ul&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techovedas.com/intel-panther-lake-set-for-2025-launch-built-on-18a-what-you-need-to-know/&quot;&gt;Panther Lake:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;~70% of logic compute tiles will be built internally&lt;br&gt;(Compared with &lt;strong&gt;0%&lt;/strong&gt; for Arrow Lake &amp;amp; Lunar Lake)&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techovedas.com/intel-nova-lake-leak-intels-monster-cpu-with-52-cores-and-15-ipc-boost/&quot;&gt;Nova Lake:&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Intel will extend the strategy to desktops&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By 2026–2027:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Desktop wafer production returns to Intel fabs&lt;br&gt;Notebook and desktop platforms both benefit&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;This dramatically reduces dependence on TSMC for client compute tiles.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h2&gt;14A: The Node That Could Restore Intel’s Process Leadership&lt;/h2&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;Even as 18A ramps, the industry is already eyeing &lt;strong&gt;14A&lt;/strong&gt;, Intel’s next-generation node featuring:&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;ul&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second-generation backside power delivery (BSPDN)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second-generation gate-all-around architecture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better electrostatic control and transistor performance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;A design that builds on lessons learned from the 18A ramp&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;Pitzer emphasized that &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://techovedas.com/14a-node-or-bust-intels-make-or-break-moment-in-the-advanced-semiconductor-race/&quot;&gt;14A yields &lt;/a&gt;and performance are already superior to 18A at comparable milestones&lt;/strong&gt;, giving IFS a realistic shot at leadership.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techovedas.com/14a-node-or-bust-intels-make-or-break-moment-in-the-advanced-semiconductor-race&quot;&gt;techovedas.com/14a-node-or-bust-intels-make-or-break-moment-in-the-advanced-semiconductor-race&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h3&gt;Fabless customer timeline:&lt;/h3&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;ul&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;Evaluation: Ongoing&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;Firm decisions on designs: &lt;strong&gt;2H26 to 1H27&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;First tape-outs could land in 2027&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;If Intel secures multiple 14A customers, it would achieve its first true foundry win against TSMC at an advanced node.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h2&gt;Why EMIB + 18A-P Could Be Intel’s Most Important Play&lt;/h2&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;Across AI accelerators, smartphones, PC processors, and automotive compute, the future is &lt;strong&gt;chiplet-based&lt;/strong&gt;. EMIB allows Intel to compete in:&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;ul&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;Multi-tile GPUs&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;AI accelerators&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;High-performance server CPUs&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;Custom silicon for hyperscalers&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;If Intel can pair &lt;strong&gt;leading-edge tiles (18A-P)&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;superior packaging (EMIB/Foveros)&lt;/strong&gt;, it could offer a differentiated model:&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Foundry + Packaging + Custom Tile Integration”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;Something TSMC does, but with less flexibility around chiplets.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;This is the foundation of Intel’s comeback.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h2&gt;Our Take: Intel’s Make-or-Break Moment Starts in Late 2026&lt;/h2&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;Intel has talked about a comeback for years. But the difference this time is &lt;strong&gt;execution plus customer interest&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;ul&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;EMIB is gaining real traction in AI accelerators&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;18A-P gives fabless customers a reason to at least evaluate Intel&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;14A could become the node where Intel proves leadership&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;Packaging is becoming Intel’s strongest differentiator&lt;/li&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;li&gt;The Tan-led regime seems more execution-focused and transparent&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;If Intel maintains yield momentum and secures anchor customers for 18A-P and 14A, the second half of 2026 could mark the beginning of a genuine revival for IFS.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techovedas.com/intel-nova-lake-leak-intels-monster-cpu-with-52-cores-and-15-ipc-boost&quot;&gt;techovedas.com/intel-nova-lake-leak-intels-monster-cpu-with-52-cores-and-15-ipc-boost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;Intel is entering a decisive phase. With Intel’s EMIB ramping in 2H26 and 18A-P/18A-PT opening up to external customers, the company is finally aligning packaging, process, and foundry strategy. If execution holds, Intel could re-emerge as a major force in advanced chip manufacturing.&lt;/p&gt; 
 
 
 
&lt;p&gt;For expert guidance and understanding semiconductor market contact @&lt;a href=&quot;https://techovedas.com/&quot;&gt;techovedas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://techovedas.com/intels-2026-emib-breakout-18a-p-opens-the-door-for-global-chipmakers/&quot;&gt;Intel’s 2026 EMIB Breakout: 18A-P Opens the Door for Global Chipmakers&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://techovedas.com&quot;&gt;techovedas&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 12:09:54 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Georgia Power says it needs a huge increase in power capacity to meet data center demand</title>
      <link>https://techxplore.com/news/2025-12-georgia-power-huge-capacity-center.html</link>
      <description>With data centers flooding into Georgia, utility regulators face a big decision: Should they let Georgia Power Co. spend more than $15 billion to increase its electricity capacity by 50% over the next six years to serve computer complexes? Or could the utility overbuild and stick other ratepayers with the bill?</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 11:47:28 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>