<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Recap News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:30:46 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
    <atom:link href="https://raw.githack.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS/main/Semiconductor-RSS.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <item>
      <title>Cooperative intermolecular interactions regulate supramolecular polymer assembly</title>
      <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-12-cooperative-intermolecular-interactions-supramolecular-polymer.html</link>
      <description>Supramolecular chemistry involves the study of self-assembly of discrete molecules that are used to build large functional structures. Often, these molecules are allowed to self-assemble into one-dimensional polymeric structures (supramolecular polymers or SPs) in a suitable environment, and the dynamic molecular interactions are noted for tweaking the environment and improving the features of the resulting SPs. They are being explored as the next-generation polymeric materials with applications in electronics, soft-robotics, nanofabrication, and biomedical fields.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://phys.org/news/2025-12-cooperative-intermolecular-interactions-supramolecular-polymer.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:25:09 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>EMASS and Semtech Collaborate on Low-Power Edge AI</title>
      <link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/emass-and-semtech-collaborate-on-low-power-edge-ai-302634491.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Integration brings LoRaWAN® connected intelligence to battery-powered industrial IoT&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;LOS ANGELES&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Dec. 9, 2025&lt;/span&gt; /PRNewswire/ -- EMASS, a Nanoveu subsidiary specializing in next-generation semiconductor technology, today announced a strategic collaboration with Semtech to bring low-power edge AI solutions integrated with LoRaWAN® connectivity to market. EMASS&apos;s ECS-DoT AI-enabled system-on-chips (SoCs) integrate Semtech&apos;s LoRa® transceivers, enabling long-range, battery-efficient intelligence for industrial, IoT, and other connected applications. The integration enables systems to process data locally, reduce network load, and deliver actionable insights in real time, even in power-constrained environments.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;span&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/#continue-jump&quot;&gt;Continue Reading &lt;br&gt; &lt;i&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/span&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; &lt;div&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/#&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;EMASS and Semtech Collaborate on Low-Power Edge AI&quot; src=&quot;https://mma.prnewswire.com/media/2839843/EMASS_Semtech.jpg?w=500&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/div&gt;  EMASS and Semtech Collaborate on Low-Power Edge AI   &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&quot;Combining ECS-DoT&apos;s on-device AI with Semtech&apos;s LoRaWAN connectivity enables autonomous sensing in environments where traditional solutions can&apos;t operate—from remote industrial sites to battery-powered security devices,&quot; said Mark Goranson, CEO of EMASS. &quot;By processing data locally and transmitting only meaningful events, this integration extends battery life and enables real-time decision-making at the edge.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&quot;LoRa transceivers extend the reach of always-on edge AI sensors to environments where traditional connectivity solutions can&apos;t operate or scale effectively,&quot; said Shahar Feldman, Semtech&apos;s senior director of wireless ICs product marketing. &quot;By working with EMASS, we&apos;re delivering practical solutions that give engineers the tools to deploy autonomous sensing at scale—whether monitoring remote industrial assets or enabling next-generation security systems.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As part of the collaboration, EMASS and Semtech are showcasing reference designs at CES 2026, demonstrating real-world applications of the integrated technology:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul type=&quot;disc&quot;&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Predictive Maintenance Demo:&lt;/b&gt; ECS-DoT edge AI, paired with Semtech&apos;s LR1121 LoRa transceiver, analyzes vibration and environmental sensor data on-device and transmits equipment health indicators over LoRaWAN to a centralized dashboard, demonstrating ultra-efficient, scalable monitoring for industrial environments.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Security Detection Demo:&lt;/b&gt; ECS-DoT performs real-time audio classification and, together with Semtech&apos;s LR1121, transmits alerts over LoRaWAN for critical acoustic events, such as glass breaks and gunshots, delivering fast, reliable detection for next-generation security devices.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attendees can view these demonstrations at CES in select locations, including the Semtech Suite (Murano 3201A, Venetian), the LoRa Alliance Booth (North Hall, Stand 10349), and EMASS&apos;s Venetian Suite.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To arrange a meeting with EMASS at CES, contact Scott Smyser: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#becdddd1cacafed0dfd0d1c8dbcb90ddd1d3&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;[email protected]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. To learn more about the ECS-DoT, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://nanoveu.com/emass/products&quot;&gt;https://nanoveu.com/emass/products&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;LoRa and LoRaWAN are registered trademarks or service marks of Semtech Corporation or its affiliates. All other trademarks mentioned in this press release are the property of their respective owners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;About EMASS&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;EMASS – a subsidiary of Nanoveu Ltd (ASX: NVU) – is an advanced semiconductor company specializing in ultra-low-power AI system-on-chip (SoC) solutions for edge computing. The company&apos;s flagship ECS-DoT chip delivers high-performance AI processing for vision, audio, and sensor data directly on-device, maximizing energy efficiency through its RISC-V architecture and non-volatile memory technologies. This always-on intelligence solution is optimized for power- and space-constrained applications including drones, wearables, healthcare devices and industrial IoT systems. For more information, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://nanoveu.com/emass&quot;&gt;nanoveu.com/emass&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;About Nanoveu&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;Nanoveu is a listed company advancing human–machine experiences at the edge through a portfolio that spans ultra-low-power AI and glasses-free 3D technologies. Its subsidiary EMASS designs advanced system-on-chip (SoC) solutions that deliver efficient, scalable on-device AI for smart devices, IoT applications and 3D content transformation – enhancing Nanoveu&apos;s reach across rapidly growing AI, edge computing and 3D content markets. EyeFly3D™ is Nanoveu&apos;s end-to-end platform for glasses-free 3D, uniting proprietary screen technology with sophisticated content processing software and, now, EMASS&apos;s ultra-low-power SoC to bring immersive 3D to a wide range of devices and industries. The Company also develops and markets an advanced range of self-disinfecting and hydrophobic films and coatings under the Nanoshield™ brand, designed for applications including large-scale CSP and photovoltaic solar installations. Together, Nanoveu&apos;s businesses deliver practical innovation that makes devices smarter, environments safer and experiences more immersive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Media Contact:  &lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;Bryar Keyes, Publitek, Senior Account Manager, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#1674646f7764387d736f7365566663747a7f62737d3875797b&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;[email protected]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Photo - &lt;a href=&quot;https://mma.prnewswire.com/media/2839843/EMASS_Semtech.jpg?p=original&quot;&gt;https://mma.prnewswire.com/media/2839843/EMASS_Semtech.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;SOURCE EMASS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://rt.prnewswire.com/rt.gif?NewsItemId=LN40805&amp;amp;Transmission_Id=202512091000PR_NEWS_USPR_____LN40805&amp;amp;DateId=20251209&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/emass-and-semtech-collaborate-on-low-power-edge-ai-302634491.html</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:19:21 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>AMD B650 Chipsets May See Reprieve in Another Sign of Memory Disruption</title>
      <link>https://www.extremetech.com/computing/amd-b650-chipsets-may-see-reprieve-in-another-sign-of-memory-disruption</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.extremetech.com/imagery/content-types/07dbHX3UyasWK8gUdiIX7jO/hero-image.fill.size_1200x675.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;hero-image.fill.size_1200x675.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;The chipset was slated to depart as B850 takes the spotlight.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.extremetech.com/computing/amd-b650-chipsets-may-see-reprieve-in-another-sign-of-memory-disruption</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 15:05:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>