<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Recap News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 23:30:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
    <atom:link href="https://raw.githack.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS/main/Semiconductor-RSS.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <item>
      <title>Congress removes right to repair language from 2026 defense bill</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/congress-removes-right-to-repair-language-from-2026-defense-bill-231708835.html?src=rss</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;According to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://pirg.org/media-center/statement-congress-strips-bipartisan-military-right-to-repair-provisions-from-defense-bill/&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; from the Public Interest Research Group, the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2026 has removed language that would have granted the US military the right to repair its own equipment rather than requiring it to use official defense contractors for maintenance. This bill is still being considered by Congress, but it is uncertain whether the right to repair language is likely to be re-introduced once it has been removed. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&quot;Despite support from Republicans, Democrats, the White House and key military leaders, troops will keep waiting for repairs they could perform themselves,&quot; US PIRG Legislative Associate Charlie Schuyler said in a statement from the organization. &quot;Taxpayers will keep paying inflated costs. And in some cases, soldiers might not get the equipment they need when they need it most.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A bipartisan bill from Senators Elizabeth Warren and Tom Sheedy was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/general/the-military-might-finally-win-the-right-to-repair-173539873.html&quot;&gt;introduced&lt;/a&gt; earlier this year to allow the military right to repair access. The topic has been a more piecemeal affair for laypeople in the US, with some states &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/oregons-right-to-repair-bill-is-now-a-law-064955635.html&quot;&gt;enacting&lt;/a&gt; their own laws and federal regulators sometimes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/ftc-warns-some-pc-manufacturers-that-theyre-violating-right-to-repair-rules-120009736.html&quot;&gt;intervening&lt;/a&gt; to offer consumers more choice in how they seek repairs. &lt;/p&gt;This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/congress-removes-right-to-repair-language-from-2026-defense-bill-231708835.html?src=rss</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/congress-removes-right-to-repair-language-from-2026-defense-bill-231708835.html?src=rss</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 23:29:12 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>PFlow Industries Highlights VRCs for Semiconductor Manufacturing Environments</title>
      <link>https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/pflow-industries-highlights-vrcs-for-semiconductor-manufacturing-environments/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pflow-industries-highlights-vrcs-for-semiconductor-manufacturing-environments</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://secure.gravatar.com/avatar/60ca50fa046b5dfa00dcdbe4afe8721fedbe411069563961be1471aa20e65faf?s=164&amp;amp;d=mm&amp;amp;r=g&quot; alt=&quot;60ca50fa046b5dfa00dcdbe4afe8721fedbe4110&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;PFlow Industries, the pioneer in vertical reciprocating conveyor (VRC) technology, highlights its VRCs, including the M Series and F Series, for the semiconductor industry.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;M Series Mechanical VRCs are engineered to deliver precise, controlled vertical movement with smooth starts and stops, protecting sensitive equipment and materials in any specialized operating environment — capabilities that are especially critical in semiconductor manufacturing and other precision-driven industries. Compatible with protocols for controlled environments, the M Series can be custom-designed to fit any facility’s layout, support integration with automated material handling systems (AMHS), and reduce manual handling. Capable of lifting up to 10,000 pounds and reaching unlimited floor levels, the M Series ensures continuous uptime and can be customized to meet the unique needs of each specific semiconductor . Manufacturers benefit from greater efficiency, safer handling, and overall reduced operational downtime.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;F Series VRC addresses the complex demands of semiconductor manufacturing, with a standard load capacity of 50,000 pounds that is customizable up to 200,000 pounds. The F Series offers unmatched carriage size flexibility and permits loading and unloading from all four sides, enabling the most flexible traffic patterns required by advanced production lines. This robust four-post lift supports frequent, high-capacity transfer of large or multiple pieces of semiconductor equipment and integrates seamlessly with facility automation systems. Built for relentless, high-demand operational cycles, the F Series assures productivity and operational continuity for years to come, while providing owners with confidence in compliance, contamination control, and long-term value.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;PFlow VRCs are more than standalone equipment; they are integrated infrastructure serving as a permanent part of facility design that delivers long-term operational resilience for semiconductor manufacturers. The robust infrastructure approach delivers strong ROI through reduced labor costs, fewer workplace injuries, and faster, safer throughput. All PFlow solutions are engineered to meet ASME B20.1 conveyor requirements, and are designed for mission-critical reliability with 24/7 operation, low maintenance, and decades of dependable performance.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;“Every industry is under cost and compliance pressure,” says Dan Hext, National Sales Director at PFlow Industries. “Our VRCs help facility operators achieve maximum throughput and efficiency while maintaining the highest levels of safety.”&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/pflow-industries-highlights-vrcs-for-semiconductor-manufacturing-environments/&quot;&gt;PFlow Industries Highlights VRCs for Semiconductor Manufacturing Environments&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.semiconductor-digest.com&quot;&gt;Semiconductor Digest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.semiconductor-digest.com/pflow-industries-highlights-vrcs-for-semiconductor-manufacturing-environments/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=pflow-industries-highlights-vrcs-for-semiconductor-manufacturing-environments</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 23:08:07 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>