<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Recap News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 14:01:27 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
    <atom:link href="https://raw.githack.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS/main/Semiconductor-RSS.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <item>
      <title>FortifyIQ Partners with Nexus-GT to Expand its Security Market Reach in Israel</title>
      <link>https://anysilicon.com/fortifyiq-partners-with-nexus-gt-to-expand-its-security-market-reach-in-israel/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dec. 09, 2025&lt;/strong&gt; –  &lt;strong&gt;The Startup-Nation is increasingly demanding highly efficient, customized classical and post-quantum cryptography. This partnership brings high-assurance system-tailored security to Israel; a “Crypto-Security Boutique.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jerusalem, Israel – December 9, 2025&lt;/strong&gt; – FortifyIQ, Inc., a provider of high-assurance hardware and software security solutions and services, announced today the signing of a representative agreement with Nexus-GT in Israel. This strategic expansion strengthens FortifyIQ’s engagement with the Israeli technology ecosystem, and ensures local companies have a dedicated point of contact to help them adopt certifiable, high-assurance cryptography and smoothly migrate to PQC (post-quantum cryptography).&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Driving Market Growth Across Critical Sectors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Nexus-GT brings extensive experience in Israel’s technology sector and will lead FortifyIQ’s efforts to support local partners, system integrators, and manufacturers across various industries, including financial systems, automotive, telecommunications, industrial IoT, medical devices, and cloud applications. This partnership will accelerate the adoption of FortifyIQ’s cryptographic hardware IPs, software libraries, and secure system architectures, particularly for applications&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;requiring high-assurance protection against physical attacks.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-Quantum Cryptography and High-Assurance Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;FortifyIQ’s solutions deliver certifiable, side-channel and fault injection attack (SCA/FIA)-hardened cryptography across AES, HMAC-SHA2, RSA/ECC, and post-quantum cryptography (PQC), in both hardware and software. Its post quantum cryptographic micro-libraries offer performance and code size on par with optimized unprotected implementations, while providing robust resistance to side-channel and fault-injection attacks.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;For customers planning hardware upgrades, FortifyIQ provides a unified API across all software and hardware PQC implementations, enabling seamless migration to hardware accelerators as next-generation chips are deployed. This approach neutralizes the “harvest now, decrypt later” threat immediately, allowing organizations to protect sensitive data today while preparing for post-quantum security in hardware.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;FortifyIQ’s high-assurance cryptography meets rigorous industry standards, ensuring that its hardware and software modules comply with strict security and certification requirements for commercial and critical infrastructure applications.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“Partnering with Nexus-GT will strengthen our ability to serve the Israeli market at a time when both post-quantum readiness and high-assurance physical attack resistance are immediate concerns,” said Alexander Kesler, Co-founder and CEO of FortifyIQ. “This local presence enhances engagement with customers across Israel.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;“I am excited to represent FortifyIQ in Israel,” said Ofir Czyzewski, founder and CEO of Nexus-GT. “The company’s unique high-assurance cryptography, hardened against side-channel and fault injection attacks, combined with its seamless migration between software and hardware, is exactly what Israeli companies need to secure sensitive data today while preparing for the post-quantum era.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://fortifyiq.com/&quot;&gt;fortifyiq.com&lt;/a&gt; or contact:&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;ul&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;Nexus-GT: Ofir Czyzewski – ofirc@nexus-gt.com / 972-747583328&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;Global Media Contact: Olivier Debelliex, VP Sales and Business Development, FortifyIQ – info@fortifyiq.com&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About FortifyIQ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;FortifyIQ engineers certifiable cryptographic IP cores, cryptographic software libraries, and roots of trust with traditional and post-quantum algorithms, all algorithmically hardened against side-channel and fault injection attacks, without compromising performance, area, or energy efficiency. Our solutions are foundry- and platform-agnostic, integrating securely across a wide spectrum, from smart cards and IoT devices to AI accelerators and cloud systems.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Backed by a strong portfolio of granted and pending patents, deep cryptographic research, and formal and practical security proofs, FortifyIQ’s IP is developed and validated using our own pre- and post-silicon EDA tools, enabling systematic evaluation of physical attack resilience.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;FortifyIQ delivers advanced cryptography that is certifiable, reliable, and built to meet the challenges of high-assurance, real-world applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://anysilicon.com/fortifyiq-partners-with-nexus-gt-to-expand-its-security-market-reach-in-israel/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:57:08 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Intel Core Ultra X9 388H Flagship Panther Lake CPU Benchmarks Leak: Trades Blows With Ryzen AI Max+ 395 In Single-Core &amp; 21% Faster Vs Core Ultra 9 285H</title>
      <link>https://wccftech.com/intel-core-ultra-x9-388h-benchmarked-on-geekbench/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/intel-core-ultra-x9-388h-benchmarked-on-geekbench/&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;406&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/Intel-Panther-Lake-Core-Ultra-X9-388H-728x406.png&quot; alt=&quot;Intel Core Ultra X9 388H Flagship Panther Lake CPU Benchmarks Leak: Trades Blows With Ryzen AI Max+ 395 In Single-Core &amp;amp; 21% Faster Vs Core Ultra 9 285H 1&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Intel Core Ultra X9 388H is showing great improvement over its predecessor, but will we see it performing similarly in other real-world applications? We will wait and see. Intel Core Ultra X9 388H Comes Out as Fast As Flagship Strix Halo in Single-Core, and Multi-Threaded Performance Remains Ahead of Core Ultra 9 285H We finally have some benchmark numbers for the flagship Intel Panther Lake chip, which gives us some idea of where to put the Ultra X9 388H in the CPU hierarchy. While Geekbench scores usually vary from test to test, it&apos;s a great start for Intel, at […]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read full article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/intel-core-ultra-x9-388h-benchmarked-on-geekbench/&quot;&gt;https://wccftech.com/intel-core-ultra-x9-388h-benchmarked-on-geekbench/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/intel-core-ultra-x9-388h-benchmarked-on-geekbench/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:52:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>H3C Launches MegaCube, A Compact NVIDIA GB10 Superchip Powered Mini PC With 128GB LPDDR5x Memory, Priced Over $5000</title>
      <link>https://wccftech.com/h3c-megacube-compact-nvidia-gb10-superchip-mini-pc-128gb-lpddr5x-5000-usd/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/h3c-megacube-compact-nvidia-gb10-superchip-mini-pc-128gb-lpddr5x-5000-usd/&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;695&quot; height=&quot;522&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/H3C-NVIDIA-GB10-Superchip-Mini-PC-_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;H3C Launches MegaCube, A Compact NVIDIA GB10 Superchip Powered Mini PC With 128GB LPDDR5x Memory, Priced Over $5000 1&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NVIDIA&apos;s GB10 Superchip sees further adoption in a brand new Mini PC, the LinSeer MegaCube, by manufacturer H3C. NVIDIA&apos;s AI-Ready GB10 Superchip Lands Inside H3C&apos;s MegaCube Mini PC, Up To 480B LLM Support The NVIDIA GB10 Superchip-powered Mini PCs are now available, starting at prices between $2500 to $3500 US. The Mini PCs come from various OEM partners, including Dell, Lenovo, HP, ASUS, MSI, Acer &amp;amp; Gigabyte. As these Mini PCs are hitting retail shelves, other manufacturers are also rolling out their own solutions based on NVIDIA&apos;s GB10 Superchip, and H3C is one of them. The company has introduced its […]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read full article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/h3c-megacube-compact-nvidia-gb10-superchip-mini-pc-128gb-lpddr5x-5000-usd/&quot;&gt;https://wccftech.com/h3c-megacube-compact-nvidia-gb10-superchip-mini-pc-128gb-lpddr5x-5000-usd/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/h3c-megacube-compact-nvidia-gb10-superchip-mini-pc-128gb-lpddr5x-5000-usd/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:52:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>iPhone Fold To Feature Technologies Not Yet Found In Apple’s Current Devices; Under-Display Camera, CoE, To Make The Cut, With Samsung Raising OLED Panel Production By 30%</title>
      <link>https://wccftech.com/iphone-fold-oled-production-increased-by-30-percent-will-feature-two-new-technologies/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/iphone-fold-oled-production-increased-by-30-percent-will-feature-two-new-technologies/&quot;&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;728&quot; height=&quot;410&quot; src=&quot;https://cdn.wccftech.com/wp-content/uploads/2025/12/iPhone-Fold-4-728x410.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;iPhone Fold OLED production raised by Samsung, with Apple&apos;s first foldable device reportedly shipping with two new technologies&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The inner OLED panel belonging to the iPhone Fold will exclusively be mass produced by Samsung, and according to the latest estimate, the premium handset could be sold in a higher volume because its panel production quantity has been increased by 30 percent. Additionally, a fresh report highlights two new technologies that will help the iPhone Fold stand out not just from the competition, but from next year’s iPhone 18 series too. Samsung to reportedly mass produce 11 million OLED panels for the iPhone Fold, with the latter possibly being Apple’s first handset to be treated to an in-screen camera and more […]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read full article at &lt;a href=&quot;https://wccftech.com/iphone-fold-oled-production-increased-by-30-percent-will-feature-two-new-technologies/&quot;&gt;https://wccftech.com/iphone-fold-oled-production-increased-by-30-percent-will-feature-two-new-technologies/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://wccftech.com/iphone-fold-oled-production-increased-by-30-percent-will-feature-two-new-technologies/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:52:04 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Intel boosts India&apos;s chip push with new Tata Group strategic partnership — includes manufacturing and packaging of Intel products for local markets</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/semiconductors/intel-boosts-indias-chip-push-with-new-tata-group-strategic-partnership-includes-manufacturing-and-packaging-of-intel-products-for-local-markets</link>
      <description>Intel’s new partnership with Tata signals a transformative step for India’s chip ecosystem, enabling domestic manufacturing, advanced packaging, and enterprise compute solutions.</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/semiconductors/intel-boosts-indias-chip-push-with-new-tata-group-strategic-partnership-includes-manufacturing-and-packaging-of-intel-products-for-local-markets</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:37:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>EU opens antitrust investigation into Google&apos;s AI practices</title>
      <link>https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/eu-opens-antitrust-investigation-into-googles-ai-practices-133015762.html?src=rss</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Google is no stranger to scrutiny from government bodies such as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/ftc-investigating-ad-sale-practices-at-google-and-amazon-160236895.html&quot;&gt;US Federal Trade Commission&lt;/a&gt; (FTC) the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/the-uks-antitrust-regulator-will-keep-a-closer-eye-on-google-search-130021994.html&quot;&gt;UK Competition and Markets Authority&lt;/a&gt; (CMA), and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/the-eus-new-charges-against-google-could-lead-to-at-least-35-billion-in-fines-165850585.html&quot;&gt;European Commission&lt;/a&gt;. Now it can add another probe to its list: The European Commission has &lt;a href=&quot;https://ec.europa.eu/commission/presscorner/detail/en/ip_25_2964&quot;&gt;opened an antitrust investigation&lt;/a&gt; into the company surrounding the content used for its AI tools. Namely, the Commission is looking into two things, starting with whether Google used web publisher&apos;s content for its AI Overview and AI Mode services — without &quot;appropriate compensation&quot; or the option to &quot;refuse&quot; the use of their materials. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Commission will investigate to what extent the generation of AI Overviews and AI Mode by Google is based on web publishers&apos; content without appropriate compensation for that, and without the possibility for publishers to refuse without losing access to Google Search,&quot; the EU executive body stated in its announcement. &quot;Indeed, many publishers depend on Google Search for user traffic, and they do not want to risk losing access to it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second prong of the Commission&apos;s investigation similarly looks into Google&apos;s potential misuse surrounding AI. It&apos;s digging into whether Google has used content uploaded to YouTube for training its generative AI models. As in the first case, the Commission &quot;is concerned&quot; that YouTube creators are not receiving proper compensation or the option to opt out of Google using their content. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In it&apos;s overview of the investigation, the Commission noted that creators have to allow Google to use their data in return for uploading media on YouTube. It added that Google&apos;s rival AI developers are unable to use any YouTube content for training their models. &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&quot;AI is bringing remarkable innovation and many benefits for people and businesses across Europe, but this progress cannot come at the expense of the principles at the heart of our societies,&quot; Teresa Ribera, EVP for clean, just and competitive transition at the European Commission, said in a statement. &quot;This is why we are investigating whether Google may have imposed unfair terms and conditions on publishers and content creators, while placing rival AI models developers at a disadvantage, in breach of EU competition rules.&quot; &lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;A Google spokesperson told Engadget that the investigation &quot;risks stifling innovation in a market that is more competitive than ever. Europeans deserve to benefit from the latest technologies and we will continue to work closely with the news and creative industries as they transition to the AI era.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;This article originally appeared on Engadget at https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/eu-opens-antitrust-investigation-into-googles-ai-practices-133015762.html?src=rss</description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.engadget.com/big-tech/eu-opens-antitrust-investigation-into-googles-ai-practices-133015762.html?src=rss</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 13:36:43 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>