<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Recap News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:30:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <!-- ADD THIS LINE BELOW -->
  <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
  <!-- KEEP THIS LINE (Self Link) -->
  <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS/refs/heads/main/Semiconductor-RSS.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <item>
      <title>To Beat China at Drug Innovation, Big Pharma and Generics Need the Supreme Court to End This Patent Absurdity</title>
      <link>https://ipwatchdog.com/2025/12/08/beat-china-drug-innovation-big-pharma-generics-need-supreme-court-end-patent-absurdity/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://ipwatchdog.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/opinion11-21.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;opinion11-21.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What&apos;s really holding America back in the biopharma race against China isn&apos;t just Beijing&apos;s subsidies or cheaper labor. It&apos;s the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit&apos;s self-inflicted wound: a court so panel-dependent that no one—brand or generic—knows which rule will apply until the panel is drawn. The Supreme Court can fix this in one stroke by granting certiorari in MSN Pharmaceuticals v. Novartis (No. 25-225) and killing the bizarre &quot;after-arising technology&quot; exception that lets old, vague patents swallow future inventions.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipwatchdog.com/2025/12/08/beat-china-drug-innovation-big-pharma-generics-need-supreme-court-end-patent-absurdity/&quot;&gt;To Beat China at Drug Innovation, Big Pharma and Generics Need the Supreme Court to End This Patent Absurdity&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipwatchdog.com&quot;&gt;IPWatchdog.com | Patents &amp;amp; Intellectual Property Law&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:18:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Nvidia reportedly wins H200 exports to China — US Department of Commerce set to ease restrictions for full Hopper AI GPU</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/gpus/nvidia-reportedly-wins-h200-exports-to-china-us-department-of-commerce-set-to-ease-restrictions-for-full-hopper-ai-gpu</link>
      <description>The U.S. government is reportedly preparing to let Nvidia ship its H200 accelerators to China, a move that could restore Nvidia’s influence in the Chinese AI market and reinforce CUDA’s dominance, but the question is if Beijing agrees to accept this hardware.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:08:21 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Navitas and Cyient partner to accelerate GaN adoption in India</title>
      <link>https://www.semiconductor-today.com/news_items/2025/dec/navitas-081225.shtml</link>
      <description>Navitas Semiconductor Corp of Torrance, CA, USA — which provides GaNFast gallium nitride (GaN) and GeneSiC silicon carbide (SiC) power semiconductors — and ASIC/ASSP and power solutions provider Cyient Semiconductor Pte Ltd of Hyderabad, India have announced a strategic long-term partnership intended to advance the adoption of GaN technology in India and establish a complete end-to-end GaN ecosystem...</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:08:15 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Nvidia Set to Win US Approval to Export H200 AI Chips to China</title>
      <link>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-12-08/nvidia-set-to-win-us-approval-to-export-h200-ai-chips-to-china</link>
      <description>The Trump administration is poised to allow Nvidia Corp. to sell its H200 artificial intelligence chip to China, according to people familiar with the matter, a move that would mark a major lobbying win for the world’s most valuable company and potentially let it regain billions of dollars of business lost in a key global market.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 20:07:56 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>