<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Recap News</title>
    <link>https://github.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS</link>
    <description>Articles for semiconductor professionals</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 18:00:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <!-- ADD THIS LINE BELOW -->
  <atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" />
  <!-- KEEP THIS LINE (Self Link) -->
  <atom:link href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/EdsonBellido/semiconductor-RSS/refs/heads/main/Semiconductor-RSS.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

    <item>
      <title>AMD&apos;s B650 chipset isn&apos;t going anywhere, according to a new rumor — rising memory costs and softening DIY demand mean the transition to B850 may take longer than expected</title>
      <link>https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/motherboards/amds-b650-chipset-isnt-going-anywhere-according-to-a-new-rumor-rising-memory-costs-and-softening-diy-demand-mean-the-transition-to-b850-may-take-longer-than-expected</link>
      <description>AMD is apparently no longer telling vendors to stop B650 production in favor of B850 (and B840) due to the current component crisis. Skyrocketing DDR5 prices have caused a steep decline in new motherboard sales, which has reportedly influenced the Red Team to continute to make and sell B650 boards for now, helping consumers still select the cheaper option.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:39:01 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Accelerate Edge AI Vision and Display Innovation with the NXP i.MX 95 Applications Processor-Based Nitrogen95 Connected SOM</title>
      <link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/accelerate-edge-ai-vision-and-display-innovation-with-the-nxp-imx-95-applications-processor-based-nitrogen95-connected-som-302635567.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;AKRON, Ohio&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span&gt;Dec. 8, 2025&lt;/span&gt; /PRNewswire/ -- Ezurio, a global leader in connectivity and embedded computing, today announces the &lt;b&gt;Nitrogen95 Connected System-on-Module&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;(SOM)&lt;/b&gt; — a high-performance vision and display platform built on the powerful NXP&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; Semiconductors i.MX 95 applications processor family. Designed for industrial, medical, and AI-enabled applications, the Nitrogen95 delivers advanced imaging, edge intelligence, and pre-certified Wi-Fi 6 + Bluetooth LE connectivity.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Built on Ezurio&apos;s proven SOM expertise, the Nitrogen95 integrates NXP&apos;s next-generation multi-core architecture, combining Cortex-A55, Cortex-M7, and Cortex-M33 processors with a dedicated 2 TOPS Neural Processing Unit (NPU) for AI acceleration. This heterogeneous compute foundation supports demanding edge workloads such as image recognition, predictive analytics, and real-time control. It conforms to the SMARC 2.2 standard form factor (82 mm × 50 mm) with onboard Ethernet PHYs, enabling scalability across processor, memory, and wireless configurations.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&quot;The Nitrogen95 Vision System embodies Ezurio&apos;s philosophy of accelerating innovation,&quot; said Robert Thompson, Director, Edge Processing Ecosystems at NXP. &quot;By leveraging the NXP i.MX 95 applications processor and pairing it with a fast, straight out of the box prototyping platform, customers can take ideas from concept to production with speed, flexibility, and confidence.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The Nitrogen95 features extensive I/O, including PCIe Gen3, USB 3.1, dual 1 Gb and 10 Gb Ethernet, CAN-FD, and GPIO, with industrial reliability from –40 °C to +85 °C and secure boot support. Its software ecosystem includes Yocto Linux, Android, and RTOS options, ensuring flexibility for diverse design environments.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;To accelerate time-to-market, Ezurio offers the &lt;b&gt;Nitrogen95 Evaluation Kit (EVK)&lt;/b&gt; — part number EZSMI-959-0816-00158-2-KC — which includes the Nitrogen95 SOM, a carrier board, a 7-inch capacitive touchscreen display, an &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4569978-1&amp;amp;h=1929356015&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ezurio.com%2Fpartners%2Ftechnology%2Farducam&amp;amp;a=Arducam&quot;&gt;Arducam&lt;/a&gt; camera module, and all required power and connectivity accessories. A non-camera version is also available. The DVK provides a complete out-of-box vision platform for evaluating performance, testing peripherals, and prototyping AI and HMI systems.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&quot;With the Nitrogen95 DVK, customers can begin development on day one,&quot; said Pejman Kalkhoran, VP of Strategic Business Development at Ezurio. &quot;It&apos;s a turnkey solution combining Ezurio&apos;s U.S.-based engineering support, integrated camera pipeline, and display technology—reducing engineering risk and dramatically accelerating deployment.&quot;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Ideal for industrial vision, robotics, medical imaging, smart displays, and edge AI cameras, the Nitrogen95 Vision System and Development Kit are available now.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;For product details, specifications, and ordering information, visit:&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4569978-1&amp;amp;h=126178415&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ezurio.com%2Fproduct%2Fnitrogen95-smarc&amp;amp;a=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ezurio.com%2Fproduct%2Fnitrogen95-smarc&quot;&gt;https://www.ezurio.com/product/nitrogen95-smarc&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Ezurio&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Ezurio turns design possibilities into reality with RF modules, system-on-modules, antennas, IoT devices, and custom solutions. With decades of expertise and a resilient global supply chain, we accelerate innovation, reduce costs, and speed time to market—your connectivity expert&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;For the latest news or more information, visit: &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4569978-1&amp;amp;h=3284238057&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.ezurio.com%2F&amp;amp;a=ezurio.com&quot;&gt;ezurio.com&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4569978-1&amp;amp;h=2663028971&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.linkedin.com%2Fcompany%2Fezurio-llc%2F&amp;amp;a=linkedin.com%2Fcompany%2Fezurio-llc%2F&quot;&gt;linkedin.com/company/ezurio-llc/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;For more information, please contact:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;Elaine BaxterPhone: +1-800-492-2320&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Email: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#6a0f060b03040f44080b121e0f182a0f101f18030544090507&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;[email protected]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;SOURCE Ezurio&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://rt.prnewswire.com/rt.gif?NewsItemId=CL36642&amp;amp;Transmission_Id=202512081205PR_NEWS_USPR_____CL36642&amp;amp;DateId=20251208&quot;&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:33:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Imec mitigates thermal bottleneck in 3D HBM-on-GPU architectures using a system-technology co-optimization approach</title>
      <link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/imec-mitigates-thermal-bottleneck-in-3d-hbm-on-gpu-architectures-using-a-system-technology-co-optimization-approach-302635561.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;&quot;This is also the first time that we demonstrate the capabilities of imec&apos;s new cross-technology co-optimization (XTCO) program in developing more thermally robust advanced compute systems.&quot; – Julien Ryckaert, imec.&lt;b&gt;About imec&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;Imec is a world-leading research and innovation hub in advanced semiconductor technologies. Leveraging its state-of-the-art R&amp;amp;D infrastructure and the expertise of over 6,500 employees, imec drives innovation in semiconductor and system scaling, artificial intelligence, silicon photonics, connectivity, and sensing.Imec&apos;s advanced research powers breakthroughs across a wide range of industries, including computing, health, automotive, energy, infotainment, industry, agrifood, and security. Through IC-Link, imec guides companies through every step of the chip journey - from initial concept to full-scale manufacturing - delivering customized solutions tailored to meet the most advanced design and production needs.&lt;p&gt;Imec collaborates with global leaders across the semiconductor value chain, as well as with technology companies, start-ups, academia, and research institutions in Flanders and worldwide. Headquartered in Leuven, Belgium, imec has research facilities in Belgium, across Europe and the USA, and with representation on three continents. In 2024, imec reported revenues of €1.034 billion. For more information, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4574047-1&amp;amp;h=997033306&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Furldefense.com%2Fv3%2F__http%3A%2Fwww.imec-int.com__%3B!!IHJ3XrWN4X8!JLRsNJKiP8GvBOP_UF2enrB-5PScTqDfDl8DSiYqL3R74CGsNqUd9bB3fChFYSWjCYXgQ5OifkLtmWLnhKazhWgm%24&amp;amp;a=www.imec-int.com&quot;&gt;www.imec-int.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:33:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Imec mitigates thermal bottleneck in 3D HBM-on-GPU architectures using a system-technology co-optimization approach</title>
      <link>https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/imec-mitigates-thermal-bottleneck-in-3d-hbm-on-gpu-architectures-using-a-system-technology-co-optimization-approach-302635548.html</link>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;&quot;This is also the first time that we demonstrate the capabilities of imec&apos;s new cross-technology co-optimization (XTCO) program in developing more thermally robust advanced compute systems.&quot; – Julien Ryckaert, imec.&lt;b&gt;About imec&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;Imec is a world-leading research and innovation hub in advanced semiconductor technologies. Leveraging its state-of-the-art R&amp;amp;D infrastructure and the expertise of over 6,500 employees, imec drives innovation in semiconductor and system scaling, artificial intelligence, silicon photonics, connectivity, and sensing.Imec&apos;s advanced research powers breakthroughs across a wide range of industries, including computing, health, automotive, energy, infotainment, industry, agrifood, and security. Through IC-Link, imec guides companies through every step of the chip journey - from initial concept to full-scale manufacturing - delivering customized solutions tailored to meet the most advanced design and production needs.&lt;p&gt;Imec collaborates with global leaders across the semiconductor value chain, as well as with technology companies, start-ups, academia, and research institutions in Flanders and worldwide. Headquartered in Leuven, Belgium, imec has research facilities in Belgium, across Europe and the USA, and with representation on three continents. In 2024, imec reported revenues of €1.034 billion. For more information, visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://edge.prnewswire.com/c/link/?t=0&amp;amp;l=en&amp;amp;o=4574047-1&amp;amp;h=997033306&amp;amp;u=https%3A%2F%2Furldefense.com%2Fv3%2F__http%3A%2Fwww.imec-int.com__%3B!!IHJ3XrWN4X8!JLRsNJKiP8GvBOP_UF2enrB-5PScTqDfDl8DSiYqL3R74CGsNqUd9bB3fChFYSWjCYXgQ5OifkLtmWLnhKazhWgm%24&amp;amp;a=www.imec-int.com&quot;&gt;www.imec-int.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 17:33:44 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>